<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
      xml:lang="en"
      xml:base="http://samjacoby.com">
    <id>http://samjacoby.com/feed/</id>
    <title>Sam Jacoby | Explorer of Stormy Seas</title>
    <link href="http://samjacoby.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>

    <author>
        <name>Neocaridina heteropoda</name>
        <email>sam@shackmanpress.com</email>
    </author>

    <updated>2019-03-09T11:04:10Z</updated>
                                            <entry>
        <title type="html">Shopcraft as Soulcraft</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/6/22/shopcraft-as-soulcraft"/>
        <updated>2015-06-22T12:06:55Z</updated>
        <published>2015-06-22T12:06:55Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/6/22/shopcraft-as-soulcraft</id>
        <summary type="html">A few thoughts on a paean to manual labor, craft, and hard-won expertise.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/shop-class-as-soulcraft&#34;&gt;Shopcract as Soulcraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; belongs to the category of things that make me feel bad about myself. It keeps company with technology executives who turn &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/07/style/escape-to-bro-topia.html&#34;&gt;treehouse builders&lt;/a&gt;, itinerant and beautifully-penniless bicycle &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bicycling.com/culture/people/ultra-romance-man-left-normal-life-behind-find-adventure&#34;&gt;adventurers&lt;/a&gt;, and Instagram feeds of lithe young people on sunwashed yacht outtings with Derrida paperbacks. If you&amp;#8217;re into that good kind of hurt (and I am), it&amp;#8217;s a solid, quick read and well-worth picking&amp;#160;up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad recently sent me a copy.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:dad&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dad&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I had thumbed through it when it was first published, thought it was interesting, and put it aside. Now that I&amp;#8217;ve been working on my own &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/motorcycles/&#34;&gt;motorcycle restoration project&lt;/a&gt;, the time seemed ripe to give it another&amp;#160;go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Per usual for this sort of thing, if you&amp;#8217;re looking for sagas from a mechanic&amp;#8217;s workbench, look elsewhere.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:zen&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:zen&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Crawford is a philospoher, and the snappy photo of a vintage &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;BMW&lt;/span&gt; on the cover aside, the subtitle, &amp;#8220;an inquiry into the value of work,&amp;#8221; is what you&amp;#8217;ll be getting. That&amp;#8217;s fine with me. There are plenty of mechanical war stories on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.sohc4.net/index.php?topic=91492.0&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SOHC4&lt;/span&gt; forums&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a programmer and designer who spends the his hours behind a computer screen, I&amp;#8217;ve always been interested in the strain of the work-philosophy genre, that assigns much of modern man&amp;#8217;s ills to dull toil in the bureaucratic labyrinths of fluorescent offices. It&amp;#8217;s a popular point of view these days. The cubicle-to-farm journey is one of the redemptive fables of our time.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:farmer&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:farmer&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The more time we spend with our devices, the more collective yearning there is for something dirtier and&amp;#160;realer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crawford takes this vague set of impulses and packages into something that makes more sense than my masculine fantasy: &lt;em&gt;I just want to get greasy and tighten bolts.&lt;/em&gt; He posits a number of points, a few of which are particularly resonant. He&amp;#8217;s highly critical of our education system for ignoring &amp;#8220;disposition.&amp;#8221; By that, he means one&amp;#8217;s predilection to say, to spend time welding than pushing pixels around. The push for mass college matriculation and the generally uniform conception white-collar professional success doesn&amp;#8217;t leave a much space for other paths outside of the absolutely fantastic.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:nba&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:nba&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I always did very well in school. It was never very difficult for me. I realize that I&amp;#8217;m lucky in that regard, but that said, it&amp;#8217;s a kind of restriction all its own. If you&amp;#8217;re achieving academically, regardless of your &lt;em&gt;disposition&lt;/em&gt;, there are a wide-range of good, well-paying jobs that are considered socially and financially&amp;#160;inappropriate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, maybe I&amp;#8217;d like to be a motorcycle mechanic. If I was a good one, I think I&amp;#8217;d be proud of me—I think my family would too. So would Matthew Crawford. But could I be one without writing a book about it? My gut tells me that few of my peers would judge me a success. I may be wrong there, actually. It just depends on who your peers&amp;#160;are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crawford also excoriates the steady degradation of labor and the rise of a poorly-defined set of &amp;#8216;soft&amp;#8217; skills that play nicely in the obtuse world of corporate cooperation. &amp;#8220;[The worker] senses what is demanded of him is not knowledge, but rather, that he project a certain kind of personality, an affable complaisance&amp;#8221; (Pg. 17). This is set of arguments that I&amp;#8217;ve always enjoyed. Robert Jackall, who Crawford quotes frequently, covers some of the same ground in &lt;em&gt;Moral Mazes&lt;/em&gt;, a must-read for anyone with an interest in how the structures of corporations affect our behavior. He contrasts the anxious corporate automaton with the mechanic, who can stand on the merit of his own work: it runs or it doesn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:doctors&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:doctors&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crawford actually quotes Michael and Ann Eisenberg, who have lab in Boulder, Colorado, is the well-spring of such research. At the meeting of electrons and hands-on competence.  &amp;#8220;Hands-on&amp;#8221;, the term, is drained of any connotation of mature competence or manual dexterity. A hands-on activity is one intended for children. Finger painting and so&amp;#160;on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s in mechanics that Crawford lightens things up. The best bits are the vivid anecdotes that provide the scaffolding for Crawford&amp;#8217;s own views. He described his time spent in testosterone-soaked speed shops, where men come together to make cars go fast, as well as casual sniping at his father, a Berkeley physicist, who focused on the theoretical to the exclusion of all else. I googled him, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berkeley.edu/news/media/releases/2003/09/10_crawford.shtml&#34;&gt;Lawrence Crawford&lt;/a&gt;—tough act to&amp;#160;follow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this, It is difficult to avoid the louche tinge of fetishism. Crawford is not above embracing it. His workshop, in a decrepit warehouse, is shared with a &amp;#8220;very sexy young S and M model.&amp;#8221; (pg. 110) His shop is even used as the site of a generic marketing photoshoot, posing a besmocked male model staring idly at a &amp;#8216;73 Ducatti. Crawford uses these to illustrate advertising&amp;#8217;s knowing manipulation of our thirst for authenticity—but Crawford is doing some of the same, albeit from the other side of the coin. I can&amp;#8217;t blame him. How many mechanics have read his book? I read it, and I&amp;#8217;d wager most do,  after a day spent hunched over a computer screen. One gets the sense that if we were spending our time repairing motorcycles , or heaving boulders, say, we would hardly be so interested. Crawford, somehow, is able to do both—motorcycles by day, philosopher by night, an easily-fetishized ideal all its own. There&amp;#8217;s another thing to feel bad&amp;#160;about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Coding and&amp;#160;Wrenching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time reading, writing, and coding. I don&amp;#8217;t make many real things. At the same time, I get the impression I do more of that kind of making then most people. I spend a large fraction of my free time wrenching on the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CB500&lt;/span&gt; (or an unloved Yamaha &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;XS400&lt;/span&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve added to the collection). That the two go together is significant. I am more patient when writing software because some problems yield to nothing else—mechanical problems are absolutely so.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:patience&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:patience&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And I have spent more time reading my motorcycle manual than that for any piece of software. I am better for one for doing the&amp;#160;other.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mark of good software design is the fully encapsulated abstraction. A black box receives a set of inputs, performs a series of operations, and returns the result. You don&amp;#8217;t need to worry about the unpleasant detail . To do the same on a 40-year old motorcycle is to court disaster. Bearings wear, bolts corrode and snap, things fall apart when they&amp;#8217;re old. Software also ages. It also breaks. Over time, as needs change, a clean abstraction begins to leak, and compromises and decisions made in its ugly core begins to surface. The software engineer is also a&amp;#160;mechanic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---
## not interesting shit
Crawford doesn&#39;t stray into this territory, and it&#39;s dangerous turf for the self-avowed liberal, but he uses masculine pronouns almost exclusively, and it&#39;s easy to gather the many of his nuanced terms under the header of &#39;manliness&#39;.

Pg. 6: Ethics of maintenance and repair
Pg. 9: Managers who now appear in the guise of therapists or live coaches
Pg. 2: Whose expert fix involves replacing an entire system beacuse some minute component has failed. 
Pg. 17Yet we all live in the same physical reality, ultimately, and owe a common debt to the world.
Pg. 82. Fixing things may be a cure for narcissism. 
--&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dad&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is actually the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; copy he&amp;#8217;s sent me. He insists otherwise.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dad&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:moral&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Jackall&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Moral Mazes&lt;/em&gt; is a jaw-dropping read, especially for those in the upwardly-ambiguous world of mid-level executives, &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:moral&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:zen&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zen &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/em&gt; is similarly misleading.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:zen&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:farmer&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9492110&#34;&gt;Death of a Programmer, Life of a Farmer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:farmer&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:nba&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years of disinterest, I have since realized that professional sports players basically have the best job. Money, fame, and physical activity. That last bit is key.  &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:nba&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:patience&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me almost a month of steady heating and cooling, tapping, and lubrication to remove the 12 frozen cylinder studs on my engine block.  Doctors also get a pass, as people who work on things they have not made.  &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:patience&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 6 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:doctors&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctors also get a pass, as people who work on things they have not made.  &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:doctors&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 7 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Rolling with Backbone + Marionette</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/5/5/backbone-marionette"/>
        <updated>2015-05-05T20:26:57Z</updated>
        <published>2015-05-05T20:26:57Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/5/5/backbone-marionette</id>
        <summary type="html">Learning something new about structuring web applications.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://formlabs.com&#34;&gt;Formlabs&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ve been putting together a new frontend application using Backbone + Marionette. I&amp;#8217;ve done a fair amount with Backbone, over the years, but have never really grasped it. I mean, I understand the basics, but the lack of prescriptive patterns has always troubled me. I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to know the right way of doing things, so the free-and-easy choices that Backbone presents has always been a bit challenging. It&amp;#8217;s not that I mind formulating my own patterns, it&amp;#8217;s that design-patterns can provide a window into the choices that an author&amp;#8217;s intentions. It helps explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; something is designed the way it is, rather than just how. I find that&amp;#160;useful.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, despite the abundance of resource:, getting started with Backbone and Marionette has been no less challenging. Thankfully, some Marionette folks have put some videos online that get a little into the modular event-driven philosophies behind what they&amp;#8217;re&amp;#160;about.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qWr7x9wk6_c&#34;&gt;The Tools &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Patterns for Building Large-scale Backbone Applications&lt;/a&gt; (Brian&amp;#160;Mann)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PrQSpdWkN6Q&#34;&gt;Building Modular &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Component Driven Architecture in Backbone.js &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Marionette.js&lt;/a&gt; (Jeremy&amp;#160;Fairbank)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EvQnntaqVdE&#34;&gt;Marionette: The Backbone Framework&lt;/a&gt; (James&amp;#160;Smith)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to start with structure.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:structure&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:structure&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve roughly followed the schematic that outlined above, starting with one simple guiding principle—one file, one responsibility. This can be onerous (150-odd files for a modest application), but as complexity has increased, it&amp;#8217;s meant that it&amp;#8217;s simple to add (and remove) functionality. A module might be roughly-organized like so, depending on the overall&amp;#160;functionality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
  user_settings
        ├── user_settings_app.js
        ├── edit
        │   ├── user_settings_edit.js
        │ ├── templates
           │   └── user_edit_list.hbs
          │   └── views
          │       └── user_edit_view.js
        ├── list
        │   ├── user_settings_list.js
        │   ├── templates
        │   │   ├── user_item.hbs
        │   │   ├── user_list.hbs
        │   │   └── user_list_layout.hbs
        │   └── views
        │       └── user_list_view.js
        ├── new
        │   ├── user_settings_new.js
        │   └── views
        │       └── user_new_view.js
        └── regions
            └── user_dialog.js
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not as bad as it looks. The &lt;code&gt;user_settings_app.js&lt;/code&gt; is the over-all showrunner, but does very little. As a sub-app, it only delegates events between the various controllers and listens to global events from other modules.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:radio&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:radio&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; , in this case, the files &lt;code&gt;user_settings_edit.js&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;user_settings_list.js&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;user_settings_list.js&lt;/code&gt;. Let&amp;#8217;s call these modules &lt;em&gt;functional controllers&lt;/em&gt;. They control the different functions of the&amp;#160;sub-application.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each functional controller furnishes the requirements necessary for rendering it&amp;#8217;s own particular view. This is where all of the messy bits go. In my case, that means fetching the relevant models and triggering other events that require &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; sub-applications to take action that are necessary for drawing the overall view.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:models&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:models&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally comes the view itself, which is only really concerned with interacting directly with the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DOM&lt;/span&gt;, capturing user-interactions, and triggering the appropriate events so that the appropriate controller (or sub-app), can respond. Though view itself includes the template, which isn&amp;#8217;t much more than a small snippet of javascript with a few variables mixed in (we&amp;#8217;ve used Handlebars&amp;#8212;the built-in underscore dependency would probably have made more&amp;#160;sense). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object data=&#34;/media/img/backbone-diagram.svg&#34; type=&#34;image/svg+xml&#34;&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is just one sub-application among many. Any larger web-application will be a constellation of interconnected modules—some handling the basics of user creation, editing, and display (like above). Others, devoted to business logic, may never be indivually routable, but only called upon to say, process a set of&amp;#160;data.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve found nice about this construction, is that though sometimes individual sub-applications can feel over-engineered (application -&amp;gt; controller -&amp;gt; view -&amp;gt; template), for fairly simple functionality like a login/logout pane, that level of complexity is fixed and&amp;#160;well-contained. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:structure&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can definitely slow you down, but it yields enormous dividends as complexity increases. I typically refactor fairly often, and a good structure means that you can iteratively refactor over your file system.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:structure&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:radio&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marionettejs/backbone.radio&#34;&gt;Backbone.Radio&lt;/a&gt; library (which used to be rolled into Marionette) to help make that happen. &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:radio&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:models&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s worth noting that in the schematic illustrated above, models and collections (entities), are defined else where and included as needed. &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:models&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Message Mondays</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/3/1/message-mondays"/>
        <updated>2015-03-01T14:08:56Z</updated>
        <published>2015-03-01T14:08:56Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/3/1/message-mondays</id>
        <summary type="html">My first FOIA request, d3.js, and Iowa DOT&#39;s sassy highway signs.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this project, I looked at the freeway digital sign alerts in Iowa charted against statewide accident totals, both obtained via &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FOIA&lt;/span&gt; requests to the Iowa&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DOT&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;spicebeam&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: right;&#34; class=&#34;source small&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iowadot.gov/&#34;&gt;Iowa&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DOT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you drive in Iowa—on the interstate, at least—you can&amp;#8217;t miss the highway alert signs. I remember seeing these growing up in &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LA&lt;/span&gt;. They were usually switched off or had a nursery rhyme reminding you to buckle up.. I never once thought, &amp;#8220;what a missed&amp;#160;opportunity!&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are not such dull thinkers in Iowa. Here, in the famously mild-mannered midwest, the highway signs have real sass. When we arrived and began our daily commute (Iowa City to Cedar Rapids), we immediately noticed the&amp;#160;signs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/p/yUdp65JmMg/&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;I often wonder about the Iowa &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DOT&lt;/span&gt; official in charge of the weekly sign&amp;#160;change.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Madison (@melizbre) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2015-01-26T14:00:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jan 26, 2015 at 6:00am &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;THE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;BLINK&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EYE&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;YOU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;COULD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DIE&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#8221; Good morning to you, too. These signs alternate with a sobering daily ticker — &amp;#8220;34 traffic deaths so far this year.&amp;#8221; Driving is serious stuff. That aside, the signs bring some humor and a note of (morbid) grace to the gray morning&amp;#160;commute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to learn more. I wanted all the&amp;#160;signs.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IowaDOT has extensive resources online, including an impressive interactive map of the state&amp;#8217;s roadways, not to mention a surprisingly comprehensive staff &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iowadot.gov/phonebook.htm&#34;&gt;phone book&lt;/a&gt;. That said, they&amp;#8217;re much more interested in relaying information about current traffic conditions than historical&amp;#160;ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got in touch with a few friendly folks out there—muckraking this ain&amp;#8217;t—and after after some back and forth, they encouraged me to file a &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FOIA&lt;/span&gt; request. With the friendly help of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://foiamachine.org&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FOIA&lt;/span&gt; Machine&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foia.gov/how-to.html&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I learned that this was a codeword for &amp;#8220;email with the magic words &amp;#8216;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FOIA&lt;/span&gt; request&amp;#8217; in it.&amp;#8221; Done. I immediately received a vacation auto-responder. Not bad. Not&amp;#160;great.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, about ten days later, an an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EXCEL&lt;/span&gt; file with 82 weeks worth of sign messages and dates was gleaming in my inbox. What I didn&amp;#8217;t have, though, was any numerical data. Another request turned that around quickly—traffic data is easy, because it&amp;#8217;s clear that agencies monitor this stuff very closely themselves. The trick, I suppose, is to get at the data that people &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; want to know. At any rate, another lovely &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;EXCEL&lt;/span&gt; file in hand, I summed by weeks (not knowing the way to do this right in Excel, I generated the appropriate sum formulas, =&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SUM&lt;/span&gt;(B7:B13) in Python and pasted em&amp;#8217;&amp;#160;in).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&#34;codehilitetable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;linenos&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;linenodiv&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c&#34;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c&#34;&gt;# print =&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SUM&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;BX&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;BX&lt;/span&gt;+n)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;interval&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;ow&#34;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;52&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;interval&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;=&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SUM&lt;/span&gt;(B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;si&#34;&gt;%d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;:B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;si&#34;&gt;%d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;interval&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ha! I felt brilliant and stupid all at once. Honestly, I find it a lot more readable than the cryptic offset(&amp;#8230;) Excel soutions, and easier than doing it all in Python. Numbers so summed, I turned to &lt;code&gt;d3.js&lt;/code&gt;, the much beloved visual library. I learned a few things in getting up to speed. Having spent quite a bit of time working with &lt;code&gt;jQuery&lt;/code&gt;, it was a pleasure to use a library that offered a bit more out-of-the-box&amp;#160;functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those looking to get into gear, the basic beginning tutorials on &lt;a href=&#34;http://d3js.org&#34;&gt;d3js.org&lt;/a&gt;—are really useful. The list of tutorials &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mbostock/d3/wiki/Tutorials&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is hit or miss, but there are some great ones too. I&amp;#8217;d recommending reading Bostock&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://bost.ocks.org/mike/join/&#34;&gt;write-ups&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://bost.ocks.org/mike/selection/&#34;&gt;joins&lt;/a&gt; more than anything else, as that explains the basics of the whole chaining syntax. I struggled somewhat with the scales, as well. It&amp;#8217;s just the kind&amp;#8217;ve thing that takes a little&amp;#160;banging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s interesting how rapidly patterns become clear. Traffic accidents spike immediately before&amp;#160;Thanksgiving.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CSV&lt;/span&gt; is available for download &lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/message_mondays.csv&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Computerese</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/1/10/computerese"/>
        <updated>2015-01-10T09:40:05Z</updated>
        <published>2015-01-10T09:40:05Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2015/1/10/computerese</id>
        <summary type="html">Useful things in Computer.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I work with computers a fair amount, so now and again want to keep track of things I&amp;#8217;ve&amp;#160;learned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sharing your localhost dev server with the&amp;#160;world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you&amp;#8217;ve got a server running locally—and want to quickly it share it with the world? You need a remote server that you have ssh access&amp;#160;to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;ssh&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;R&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;remote&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;localhost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;sjacoby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;@&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;remote&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to enable &lt;code&gt;GatewayPorts&lt;/code&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;remote&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;sshd_config&lt;/code&gt; (not your local&amp;#160;machine):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;GatewayPorts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reload the remote sshd for the new config (on my Arch box, it&amp;#8217;s the&amp;#160;below).:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;systemctl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;restart&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;sshd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your locahost page should now be available at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;my remote server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;my remote port&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Party&amp;#160;on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pretty printing &lt;code&gt;json&lt;/code&gt; responses,&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve got this little slice of&amp;#160;sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;tool&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want to do it in Vim, go&amp;#160;with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:%!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;tool&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pascalprecht.github.io/2014/07/10/pretty-print-json-in-vim/&#34;&gt;Pascal Prect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Deleting Annoying&amp;#160;Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;find . -name &amp;#8216;.DS_Store&amp;#8217; -delete
  find . -type&amp;#160;l&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Hiking the Gros Morne Long Range Traverse</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2014/12/5/hiking-gros-morne-long-range-traverse"/>
        <updated>2014-12-05T18:54:40Z</updated>
        <published>2014-12-05T18:54:40Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2014/12/5/hiking-gros-morne-long-range-traverse</id>
        <summary type="html">In which modest men conquer modest mountains</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;A group of my friends periodically comes together in (increasingly) far-flung parts of the world to remind each other of our mutual affection. The most recent round took us to Newfoundland, a ragged slash of land off the Eastern coast of Canada. The ostensible object was the Long Range Traverse, a trail across the mountains that run the length of Newfoundland&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pc.gc.ca/eng/pn-np/nl/grosmorne/index.aspx&#34;&gt;Gros Morne National Park&lt;/a&gt;. This was as unlikely a mission as any for this particular crew. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t say that we&amp;#8217;re wholly unathletic, but it&amp;#8217;s not what springs to mind. That said, we&amp;#8217;re all reasonably competent at  various things—from television trivia to expounding conservative ideology—so with a bit of prep (see below), it worked out. It was pretty,&amp;#160;too.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Before&amp;#160;Leaving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reserve flights to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;YDF&lt;/span&gt;, Deer Lake. These cost a small fortune. All of our flights went through&amp;#160;Toronto.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LRT&lt;/span&gt; permit reservations with the Gros Morne park office. Another small fortune ($80 each or&amp;#160;so)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hotel reservations on either side. We went with the Holiday Inn Express, which was definitely the top-end of the market. That&amp;#8217;s just how we&amp;#160;roll. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Car rental for the duration, though it spent most of the time sitting in the trailhead parking lot. Seemed essential&amp;#160;nonetheless. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduling &amp;#8220;taxi&amp;#8221; drop-off at Western Brook Pond&amp;#160;trailhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting map &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; waypoints (I actually didn&amp;#8217;t see these for sale at the welcome center, but could&amp;#8217;ve missed&amp;#160;them).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reserving ferry tickets to be dropped off at trailhead. Actually, not sure if these were reserved. Jesse definitely checked the times&amp;#160;though. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was about it, I believe. I didn&amp;#8217;t do any of this. I mostly confined myself to perusing various online travel guides and figuring out how to use a little &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; gadget I&amp;#8217;d purchased for the occasion. After some wrangling, I managed to load on the free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibycus.com/ibycustopo/&#34;&gt;Ibycus Topo Maps&lt;/a&gt;, that provide detailed coverage of all of Canada. For those new to the world of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; devices and the like, it&amp;#8217;s a pain—a network of proprietary devices and file formats, custom-made tools for conversions, well-intentioned corporate efforts at cross compatibility, etc. For good measure, I also ordered the necessary (paper) topo map as a fall-back&amp;#160;(012H12-P). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: all of the photos here are courtesy of my dear friend Anton, who among his many talents, is a fantastic photographer. Thanks,&amp;#160;Anton!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 0: Getting&amp;#160;Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assembled at Deer Lake, where the airport is, but that&amp;#8217;s a solid hour or so from Gros Morne itself. Joe&amp;#8217;s flight was delayed, which made it mildly more complex. And there was some kind of elaborate blasting operation taking place on the single road to Grose Morne, so we ended up arriving at the visitor center towards the end of the day. I don&amp;#8217;t know why I thought it&amp;#8217;d be less developed, but it was one of those solid, rustic buildings with carpet and bits of antler and&amp;#160;everything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15837583256/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some pre-trip pontificating. Waiting for Joe to&amp;#160;land.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After announcing that we had reservations for the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LRT&lt;/span&gt;, we were directed over to a sunken auditorium, where a somber video introduced us to the trail. This was the first indication that thing wouldn&amp;#8217;t be quite as rugged as anticipated. How many trails have full-blown taped&amp;#160;introductions?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The&amp;#160;Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get issued tickets for the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LRT&lt;/span&gt;, you&amp;#8217;ve got to pass a written basic wilderness navigation exam. We were all a bit nervous about this, having essentially zero experience. The internet had various rumblings about it; it didn&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;seem&lt;/em&gt; difficult, but some hikers had been delayed while trying to convince the rugged characters up there that they were fit to take the trail. That, and the standard issue emergency &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; beacon that everyone is issued gave the endeavour a serious, dramatic&amp;#160;air. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15837588086/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great minds assemble (this photo, and every other, courtesy of Anton&amp;#160;Troianovski).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigation-wise, after watching a few YouTube videos and trying to wrap my mind around declination and such, I felt reasonably prepared. We needn&amp;#8217;t of worried. The test itself is only 20 or so questions, a few typewritten sheets: take various readings off of a map, identify where you might read the scale, measure the declination,  grade-school stuff. While I&amp;#8217;d imagined we&amp;#8217;d be in a room with a stern, weathered Canadian outdoorsman, the whole affair was much more casual. We got to take the test off to a table in the visitor center and work together as a group. And the particular photocopy we&amp;#8217;d been issued happened to have the answer key stapled to the reverse. Oops. I pointed this out to the rangers when we returned it to the desk, so I imagine that particularly oversight has been corrected (sorry), but overall, it wasn&amp;#8217;t a big&amp;#160;deal.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed with flying colors, though I&amp;#8217;ll admit, that doesn&amp;#8217;t prove much. And it seemed like we had a better sense of some of the answers than the ranger. Passed, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;. But I wasn&amp;#8217;t exactly sure how we were going to cope on the&amp;#160;trail.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a solid dinner at Earle&amp;#8217;s (at least I thought so)—Moose Burgers, Peanut Butter milkshakes, and other assorted Newfie delicacies—and we spent the night at a campground that Anton had scoped out, Green Point, just north of&amp;#160;town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15837596016/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fish &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; brewis w/&amp;#160;scrunchions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nice, developed campground. We got there a bit late in the day to really enjoy the beach, but it was a beautiful spot. We divied up some supplies, food, etc., in the back of our rented minivan. I, of course, was stressed about the relative weight distribution, as well as the self-appointed navigator dude, somewhat apprehensive about the&amp;#160;&amp;#8216;morrow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1: We&amp;#160;Begin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove out to the end-point of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LRT&lt;/span&gt;, which is just a few minutes from the visitors center. Most people do it this way—North to South—and were met there by a pair of friendly locals who moonlight a &amp;#8220;taxi&amp;#8221; service. Jesse made the reservations, I think, so I don&amp;#8217;t recall the exact details. I do know that one of the fellows ran Pittman&amp;#8217;s Restarurant in Norris Point. Or maybe Pittman&amp;#8217;s Inn in Rock Harbor. Something like&amp;#160;that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They charged, I believe, $20 each, which like most things in Newfoundland, seemed a bit steep, but what-the-hey. Anyhow, the system worked well enough. We piled in and they drove us up to Western Brook Pond, where we&amp;#8217;d been instructed to begin the trip. The Pond is a capped fjord, a long jet of water between steep cliffs. After being dropped off by our drivers (who gamely snapped our photo), we walked the mile-or-two of boardwalk that spans the swamp between the coast and the pond. Upon arrival, we encountered our first mini fiasco: a gruff, intimidating ship captain, who eyeing our packs, informed us that we&amp;#8217;d screwed up—the 11:30 ferry was too big to stop at the small dock that we&amp;#8217;d have to be dropped off at: we were supposed to be on the small boat that only left at&amp;#160;9:&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;00AM&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesse, our planner-in-chief, was disconsolate. He&amp;#8217;d called and asked this very question, and the woman he spoke to had insisted just the opposite. Nevertheless, despite the warning, the boat boss said &amp;#8220;he&amp;#8217;d do his best to drop us off,&amp;#8221; leaving off with a significant shrug. What would happen if we didn&amp;#8217;t manage to get to the trailhead wasn&amp;#8217;t immediately clear. No matter; we bought our tickets—$33 dollars apiece. We&amp;#8217;d cleverly left our credit cards behind in the car (what kind&amp;#8217;ve backwoods adventurer carries plastic?) so in another panicked moment, we pooled our emergency cash reserves and came up with the request $&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;200CAD&lt;/span&gt; or so. Off we went! Every place we went too was happy to take &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt; (along with the favorable exchange&amp;#160;rate).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was great and the ferry ride was lovely. Concern over the drop-off gradually dissipated. It seemed clear that there was some element of manly psuedo-drama in the captain&amp;#8217;s warning: we&amp;#8217;d met a trio of hikers who&amp;#8217;d be starting down the trail with us who were in the same situation. We also met another fellow from Somerville, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MA&lt;/span&gt; (Union Square, actually), on some intermediary leg of a vast cross-continental tour (and from whom Mishy immediately extracted various personal details—&amp;#8221;Will you and your girlfriend get married?&amp;#8221;&amp;#160;Maybe.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15676077580/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sights!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15675899018/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Left to our fate at the end of Western Brook&amp;#160;Pond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15677407959/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting&amp;#160;off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drop-off wasn&amp;#8217;t anything to worry about after all. The captain brought the boat around slowly, and though they didn&amp;#8217;t tie down, we easily stepped off on to the dock. We paused there for a moment, and after getting our bearings and clicking &amp;#8220;go&amp;#8221; on the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, set off. A very clearly marked trail led us up the gorge, through thick, almost tropical growth. As we ascended the gorge, the path become somewhat less clear—but it was tough to get lost. The gorge was narrow, and well, we were just going up&amp;#160;it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few miles from the trailhead, this was, funnily enough, where we go the most lost—or at least, half of us did. Time and again, we&amp;#8217;d been told to &amp;#8220;go right&amp;#8221; at the waterfall. We kept our eyes peeled. When the opportunity presented itself, it was pretty clear what right was — a sheet of water slid across the center of the gorge. To left was a reasonably-sheer cliff. We went right. Too far right, it turns out. Mishy, Joe, &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; I found ourselves gnarled in a thick nest of tuckamore — the technical term for wiry, nearly-impassable scrub of stunted trees that was a fixture of the&amp;#160;trip. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15243791783/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking back at Western Brook&amp;#160;Pond&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We weren&amp;#8217;t lost, per se, just a little off the trail. It wasn&amp;#8217;t pleasant. Hacking through the thick scrub hurts. I picked some scratches or bites or something, that I ended up carrying fora couple of weeks after. At length, we made it back to the trail, rejoining our merry fellows. So challenges, we decided to camp in the bowl at the top of the gorge—which after a group photo, clouded in. We cooked and made camp, bracing ourselves for the poor weather we knew was to&amp;#160;come.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15241162424/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading Evelyn Waugh. I know,&amp;#160;right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2: We&amp;#160;Endure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke in the fog. It was cold and wet, though not yet rainy. That would come later. This was the worst day. It was  about as close as I&amp;#8217;ve gotten to a bit of a &amp;#8220;situation&amp;#8221;, but I&amp;#8217;m also a little paranoid. We did seem to be on the verge of hypothermia at certain points, though&amp;#8230;Starting out, all was rosy. It took some doing to even figure out the best route out of the bowl. We clicked around ineffectually on the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, and tried to read the wet, creased map—but we did&amp;#160;fine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting out from the top of the gorge, we were surprised by how much longer it took us to make it to the Little Island Pond campground. Good thing we decided to camp early.  We checked out what we&amp;#8217;d been missing — wet, leaf-covered platforms and a nice, open-air toilet. The trail, in general, was very well-marked. We did refer to the map, compass, and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, but honestly, it would&amp;#8217;ve been tough to get lost, at least in the first part of the day. We speculated that it was because it was so late in the season (mid-September), that the trail had been beaten-pretty well in. Also, no bugs. After what I&amp;#8217;d read about black flies and the like, that was great. I don&amp;#8217;t even think I went for my bug spray once, or the various mosquito nets I&amp;#8217;d&amp;#160;packed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15861476461/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Puzzling over the map. Everything kind&amp;#8217;ve looked the&amp;#160;same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15676140890/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anton on&amp;#160;Orange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After passing Little Island Pond, we pushed on to Hardings. This was the toughest stretch of the day, and probably the trip — an endless succession of water-soaked meadows, muddy pits, and stream crossings, all in an intermittent freezing rain. We did spot a few rainbows along the way, but it turned windier and the rain turned colder as the day wore on, and by the late afternoon, we were very cold and soaking wet.. I don&amp;#8217;t think we caught more than a glimmer of sunshine all&amp;#160;day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15241182304/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rainbow over alpine&amp;#160;marshes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15861462231/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mud. Mud.&amp;#160;Mud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15243810643/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;An athletic&amp;#160;moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we were coming descending to Hardings Pond we were miserable. At the lake&amp;#8217;s edge, we passed the other three hikers who we were sharing the trail with. They had set-up camp against the wall of a rangers&amp;#8217; hut—clearly closed—on the shore. It looked like they were boiling water in the outhouse. It was &lt;em&gt;cold&lt;/em&gt;.  They waved us merrily on, and we trudged grimly through the mud, hoping for a sheltered camping&amp;#160;spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15677456149/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soaking next to Hardings&amp;#160;Pond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing to be found — the platforms on Hardings Pond are clustered along an exposed beach. Beautiful, no doubt, in fine weather. It didn&amp;#8217;t look like it now. Mishy had started uncontrollably shivering. Joe followed. We set-up the tents side-by-side on the tent platform to create a little area screened from the wind. It kinda worked, and at least, with the tents up, we were protected from the cold. Recovery was on the&amp;#160;way.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3: We See a&amp;#160;Moose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning was&amp;#160;sunny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15243822813/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morning at Hardings Pond(photo courtesy of Anton&amp;#160;Troianovski).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were getting moving, the other hikers cheerfully passed us: &amp;#8220;We were worried about you guys last night!&amp;#8221; Yeah. Sure. What were they expecting to find? Our frigid little bodies, desperately spooning in the Gros Morne mud? At any rate, we were triumphant and so fortified by survival, forged on. Hump day. Battle legs forged, the planw as to push on, well, as far as we could. At this point, somewhat to our surprise, we&amp;#8217;d scarely made it half-way. The blithe travelogs of the more capable taunted us, as we scrambled to make up&amp;#160;time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I would say, was also the first real &amp;#8220;trail-less&amp;#8221; day. Much had been made, with the test, the emergency beacons, etc., of how there wasn&amp;#8217;t much of a trail. That wasn&amp;#8217;t our experience. For most of the trip, we followed a well-marked and fairly obvious trail. Along ridges, there were often cairns, and in some dense forested portions, pink-flagged ribbons marked tricky passages. In general, by West Coast standards, I&amp;#8217;d say, this was a well-marked trail. Perhaps not like the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AT&lt;/span&gt; or something, flagged by distinctive blazes or signs—but still pretty good. This day was the tricky one, as it were, but we were patient with the maps and the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, and never got too far out track. We had a few good moments of &amp;#8220;rediscovering&amp;#8221; the path, but nothing ever got particularly dire. We also saw a moose! A huge bull standing probably 50 yards off the trail. He moved fairly quickly off into the tuckamore, but we got a good long look. Though we saw a lot of tracks, we never saw any&amp;#160;elk.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15677361429/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-grade navigational&amp;#160;despotism&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did run into a dicey spot, but teamwork (and A-plus photojournalism)&amp;#160;prevailed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://samjacoby.com/media/files/newfoundland.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point late in the afternoon, Jon&amp;#8217;s boot disintegrated entirely. After four days of constant moisture, the rubber sole just fell off. Pretty miserable. He swapped into some crocs, but that didn&amp;#8217;t seem much better. Wet, wet, and&amp;#160;nasty. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redemption came, though, in where we decided to camp that night, on a bustery cliff overlooking an astonishing&amp;#160;gorge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15837552716/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overlooking some magnificent&amp;#160;spot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15676017440/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Huddling for&amp;#160;warmth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15241067984/in/photostream/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hot cocoa, moonlight,&amp;#160;manliness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had couscous and sausage, which was delicious (though instantly cold). Anton made some little European tea and jamm&amp;#160;thing.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 4: A&amp;#160;Return&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From where we&amp;#8217;d camped, we were already on the high-plateau just north of Gros Morne itself. We had a solid hike ahead, but there wasn&amp;#8217;t much concern that we&amp;#8217;d be lost or not make it. I think we were all pretty ready to call it quits, though. The descent into Ferry Gulch was a little harrowing, a vertical scramble anchored by muddy roots. One of the least pleasant parts of the entire hike, really, was the walk out from under Gros Morne, which was a couple of miles on loose scree, followed by another hour or so through low, enclosed forests to the&amp;#160;trailhead.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15676008250/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;451&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuckered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/15693875339/player/&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;604&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;We started at the top. Not quite N-S, by the&amp;#160;way&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our Gros Morne &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LRT&lt;/span&gt; waypoints: &lt;a href=&#34;http://samjacoby.com/media/files/gros_morne_lrt.gpx&#34;&gt;[.gpx]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://samjacoby.com/media/files/gros_morne_lrt.kml&#34;&gt;[.kml]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Motorcycles</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/motorcycles/"/>
        <updated>2014-10-21T23:30:01Z</updated>
        <published>2014-10-21T23:30:01Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/motorcycles/</id>
        <summary type="html">In which I discover what everyone else already knew</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/fall-cb500.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall ride outside of&amp;#160;Boston.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obeying a widely-known primordial need within the soul, I acquired a 1972 Honda motorcycle in the summer of 2013. It was (then) a 41 year-old machine and requires continuous attention. That is part of the fun. This is mostly a place for me to keep track of&amp;#160;notes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found great satisfaction in working on it: tracing down corroded electrical connections, adjusting the timing &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; valves, rebuilding the cylinders—a nice change of pace from the technological-computer arts where I usually find&amp;#160;myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;right-hand-switch&#34;&gt;Right-Hand Switch&amp;#160;Rebuild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;starter-solenoid&#34;&gt;Starter Solenoid&amp;#160;Rebuild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;top-end-rebuild&#34;&gt;Top-End&amp;#160;Rebuild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;clutch&#34;&gt;Clutch&amp;#160;Cleanup &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;super-sport&#34;&gt;1979 Honda &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CB750F&lt;/span&gt; Super&amp;#160;Sport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Maintenance&amp;#160;Table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working my way down this, little by little. It&amp;#8217;s pretty&amp;#160;handy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/10817763986/&#34; title=&#34;HSM500550_9 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7405/10817763986_cd48417a9f.jpg&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;HSM500550_9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;From when charts were&amp;#160;king.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Parts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front Tire: Bridgestone Spitfire S11, 100/90 &lt;em&gt;(Fall&amp;#160;2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rear Tire: Bridgestone Spitfire S11, 110/90 &lt;em&gt;(Fall&amp;#160;2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carbs: 627B Keihin (#100 mains, #40 pilots — &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;replacements).  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aftermarket 4-into-1, ceramic-coated black (Evid Mad Headers,&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NYS&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Points: New &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TEC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt; points (replacing&amp;#160;Diachi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;APE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; Cylinder&amp;#160;Studs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt; Honda Head&amp;#160;Gasket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vesrah Gasket&amp;#160;Kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stainless hex hardware&amp;#160;throughout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Compression&amp;#160;Check&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cyl 1: 120
cyl 2: 120
cyl 3: 130
cyl 4:&amp;#160;130&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Work&amp;#160;Log&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I should be keeping a dated worklog &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s just a useful thing to do. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing it by hand, but what else is the internet&amp;#160;for? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Work&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Changed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil filter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;July 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clutch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clutch cover opened, cleaned, clutch adjusted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Petcock&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fuel filter screen checked&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fuel lines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gas line replaced (with 5.5mm original)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Septemer 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tires&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced tires (Bridgestone S11), professionally-mounted &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; balanced&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;November 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spark plugs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced original plugs with new &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NGK&lt;/span&gt; 12mm &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;D7EA&lt;/span&gt;; new boots as well&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;November 2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Contact points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checked &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; adjusted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cam chain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adjusted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Valves&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checked &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; adjusted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Petcock&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rebuilt and cleaned (again). Shouldn&amp;#8217;t be leaking anymore.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Airbox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cover added from parts bike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hardbags&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Added a pair of white Shoei&amp;#8217;s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Changed, Castrol 10W-40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seals&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced right-crank gasket&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clutch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checked clutch plates for warping, wear&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clutch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced clutch cable &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; lifter rod.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ignition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rebuilt key assembly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fork&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced fork seals &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; changed fork oil&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Changed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil Filter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil Pump&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replace oil pump seals&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;September 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oil Switch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced leaking oil pressure switch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;September 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Front Caliper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replace piston seal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;January 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Motor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Removed. Whew!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Motor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disassembled Head&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Motor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Removed cylinder studs (ouch)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tank&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sealed w/ Eastman 2K Clearcoat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Motor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Valves reground, new seats cut (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MAS&lt;/span&gt; Machine, Iowa City&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Motor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Painted &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; reassembled top-end w/ new Versah gaskets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chassis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tapered steering bearings (previous owner installed)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Baggage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Machined new&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;March 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fuel System&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Broke down carburetors &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; cleaned; replaced all rubbers; cleaned &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt; brass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shocks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced stock shocks w/ new HAGONs (200lb load)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fairing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Installed Vetter Windjammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Electric&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replaced dash lights with LEDs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fuel System&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pipes ceramic coated (Evil Mad Headers, New York)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fuel System&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rejetting 627B carbs w/ Keihin #40 pilots&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.sohc4.com&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SOHC4&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Cb350-550Cc-1971-1978-Clymer-Motorcycle-Manuals/dp/0892876530/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1383324794&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=cb500+clymer&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CB500&lt;/span&gt; Clymer&amp;#160;Manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sohc4.net/cb500-manuals/&#34;&gt;Honda &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CB500&lt;/span&gt; Manuals&lt;/a&gt; (Courtesy of&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SOHC4&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nehondaguys.info/&#34;&gt;New England Honda&amp;#160;Guys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:zen-1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never read it. Hear it&amp;#8217;s not really about motorcycles. Update 05/27/2015. Read it. Is kind&amp;#8217;ve about motorcycles.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:zen-1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Squares</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/squares"/>
        <updated>2014-07-09T17:00:54Z</updated>
        <published>2014-07-09T17:00:54Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/squares</id>
        <summary type="html">Drawing some squares in JavaScript &amp; firebase.io.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/squares/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Squares.js&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/squares.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my ongoing journey of self-improvement, I made a little thing. In a relative first for me, I did it without including all of the fancy libraries. It also uses Firebase, which is a pretty neat, simple thing. Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;/squares/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will probably work until &lt;a href=&#34;http://firebase.com&#34;&gt;firebase&lt;/a&gt; decides it&amp;#160;shouldn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">The Nica Times</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/nicatimes"/>
        <updated>2014-02-20T15:22:46Z</updated>
        <published>2014-02-20T15:22:46Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/nicatimes</id>
        <summary type="html">Journalistic sojourns in Central America</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I wrote for &lt;a href=&#34;http://ticotimes.net&#34;&gt;The Tico Times&lt;/a&gt; or rather, it&amp;#8217;s Nicaraguan imprint, The Nica Times (now defunct), for six months or so while living in Nicaragua. On my fast-improving college Spanish, I covered a murder trial (the first which brought the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FBI&lt;/span&gt; to Nicaragua—imperialism at work), anti-government protests, and reforestation&amp;#160;projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_pronica.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_pronica.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group Helps Create ‘Oasis’ at La Chureca — August 24,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_catarina.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_catarina.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catarina Looks to Expand Upon Budding Success — August 3,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_ineter.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_ineter.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country Braces for Hurricane Season — July 27,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_march.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_march.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizen Councils Suffer Defeat in National Assembly — September 14,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_develop.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_develop.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Developments Seek Social Sustainability — September 28,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_euro.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_euro.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expats Find Starting a Business Workable — August 31,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_penasblancas.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_penasblancas.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; Gives Police Anti-Drug Aid Package — July 20,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_perspective.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_perspective.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managua: The Good, the Bad and Gallo Pinto — July 20,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_judd.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_judd.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Reforestation Project Takes Root — July 27,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_onetree.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_onetree.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Book Urges Folks to See Trees Through Forest — August 10,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_hipica.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_hipica.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granada Still Bullish for its Religious Festivals — August 10,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_lake.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_lake.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coastal Cleanup Helps Change Litterbug Culture — August 31,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_lemon.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_lemon.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granada Expats Relieved by Verdict —  August 31,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_garden.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_garden.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granada’s New Garden Café Keeps it Simple with Sandwiches — September 7,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_plazacolon.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_plazacolon.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hotel Plaza Colón Unveiled in All its Glory — September 14,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_solar_clear.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_solar_clear.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women’s Group Promotes Solar Cooking — September 14,&amp;#160;2007 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_youth_program_chess.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_youth_program_chess.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youth Program Seeks Next Chessmaster — January 4,&amp;#160;2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_activists.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_activists_against_abortion.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activists Mobilize Against Abortion Ban — October 5,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_internet.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_internet.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet Potential Remains Untapped — October 19,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/nicatimes/sjacoby_local_bloggers.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/nicatimes/sjacoby_local_bloggers.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local Bloggers Make Their Mark on the Web — October 25,&amp;#160;2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Computer Scientists&#39; Websites Look Terrible</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/10/17/computer-scientists-websites-look-terrible"/>
        <updated>2013-10-17T23:25:44Z</updated>
        <published>2013-10-17T23:25:44Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/10/17/computer-scientists-websites-look-terrible</id>
        <summary type="html">And they don&#39;t give a damn.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/media/img/old-internet.png&#34;/&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;What hath man&amp;#160;wrought!?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always taken pleasure in the fact that the websites of most computer scientists are abysmal. This is because they write them themselves and they don&amp;#8217;t give a damn what you think. They have better things to do. Like write&amp;#160;Python.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growing selection in casually-alphatetical&amp;#160;order: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/users/hal/&#34;&gt;Hal Ableson&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;Education, Freedom&amp;#160;Defender&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eecs.harvard.edu/~dbrooks/&#34;&gt;David Brooks&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;Taught me the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomasulo_algorithm&#34;&gt;Tomasulo&amp;#160;Algorithm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.billbuxton.com/&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton&lt;/a&gt; Did your project in the&amp;#160;80s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/People/Berners-Lee/&#34;&gt;Tim Berners-Lee&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;WWW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ohio.edu/people/mc412897/finalproject.html&#34;&gt;Vint Cerf&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;cerf-1-mark&#34; href=&#34;#cerf-1-note&#34;&gt;†&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;Internet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corradobohm.it/Corrado_Bohm/Home.html&#34;&gt;Corrado Böhm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;metacircular evaluation never looked so&amp;#160;good&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.princeton.edu/~bwk/&#34;&gt;Brian Kernighan&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;C  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu/~uno/&#34;&gt;Donald Knuth&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;Couple of big&amp;#160;books&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://moolenaar.net/&#34;&gt;Bram Moolenaar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;I vim&amp;#160;you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tufts.edu/~nr/&#34;&gt;Normal Ramsey&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt; Luxuriant&amp;#160;Hair&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cm.bell-labs.com/who/dmr/&#34;&gt;Dennis Ritchie&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt; C &lt;em&gt;in&amp;#160;memorium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.python.org/~guido/&#34;&gt;Guido van Russum&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;Python&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.princeton.edu/~rs/&#34;&gt;Robert Sedgewick&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt; Algorithms. A particular&amp;#160;classic.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stallman.org/&#34;&gt;Richard Stallman&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;#160;Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stroustrup.com/&#34;&gt;Bjarne Stroustrup&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt;&amp;#160;C++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.bell-labs.com/who/ken/&#34;&gt;Ken Thompson&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;desc&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UNIX&lt;/span&gt;, B,&amp;#160;Go&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got others? Drop me a note: sam@shackmanpress.com 
&lt;div id=&#34;cerf-1-note&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;†. &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, not his. But still&amp;#160;amazing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-note-number&#34; href=&#34;#cerf-1-mark&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Drawing the Electric</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/storyclip"/>
        <updated>2013-08-22T12:57:30Z</updated>
        <published>2013-08-22T12:57:30Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/storyclip</id>
        <summary type="html">Conductive ink as an expressive medium for narrative storytelling and interaction design.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/tapclip-project-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drew this one myself, giving it that weird kids-drawing-by-grownup&amp;#160;vibe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/tapclip/&#34;&gt;TapClip&lt;/a&gt; allowed for a general purpose-abstraction of interface design—anything conductive could serve as input. I&amp;#8217;d done a fair amount of work with &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/paper-sensors/&#34;&gt;conductive paints&lt;/a&gt;, which was a lot of fun, and I wanted to see what happened when the tight constraints of sensor design were lifted. I ran a series of workshops with a variety of participants, who were provided with conductive paints alongside conventional art supplies. It was, to say the least, a challenging&amp;#160;experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At my Sparkfun workshop, I&amp;#8217;d worked with &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/sparkfun/&#34;&gt;technology educators and makers&lt;/a&gt;, a patient lot if there ever was one. Kids are another matter. Fresh-out-of-the-lab tech hasn&amp;#8217;t necessarily been made for the kind of abuse that 7-10 year olds heap on it. It made me respect the work of the folks who make toys all the more. Kids expect things to work&amp;#160;right.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, we certainly learned a lot in the process. Ultimately, I summarized what we&amp;#8217;d done with the board into a submission for &lt;strong&gt;Interaction Design &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Children 2013&lt;/strong&gt;, taking place in New York City. Happily it was accepted. You can download it for your reading pleasure&amp;#160;below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drawing the Electric: Storytelling with Conductive Ink&lt;/strong&gt;, Sam Jacoby &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Leah Buechley, &lt;strong&gt;Interaction Design and Children ’13&lt;/strong&gt;, June 24–27, 2013, New York City, New York, United States. &lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/sjacoby_idc2013.pdf&#34;&gt;(pdf)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Drawing the Electric Synth</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/4/2/sparkfun-workshop"/>
        <updated>2013-04-02T12:19:50Z</updated>
        <published>2013-04-02T12:19:50Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/4/2/sparkfun-workshop</id>
        <summary type="html">A workshop at SparkFun Electronics.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a compendium of resources assembled for a workshop over the weekend of April 6 and 7 at SparkFun Electronics in Boulder,&amp;#160;Colorado.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Workshop&amp;#160;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore conductive inks and other materials to create unique, interactive musical instruments. Learn the basics of embedded microcontroller programming and circuit design, while crafting miniature synthesizers using a combination of electronics, programming, and art materials. For those interested, we can delve into the mysteries of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FM&lt;/span&gt; sound generation and work on creating structed, pictorial representations of sound. No experience necessary—but you’ve got to love crafts, drawing, sound, and learning new ways of making&amp;#160;electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#surveys&#34;&gt;Surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#paper-speakers&#34;&gt;Paper&amp;#160;Speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tinyprogrammer&#34;&gt;TinyProgrammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tinysynth&#34;&gt;TinySynth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#mosfet&#34;&gt;Adding Amplification with a&amp;#160;Mosfet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#battery-holder&#34;&gt;Battery&amp;#160;Holder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#helpful-information&#34;&gt;Helpful&amp;#160;Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#it-happened&#34;&gt;It&amp;#160;Happened&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;surveys&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Surveys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our ongoing research at &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;High-Low Tech&lt;/a&gt; and my own thesis, there is a pre-and-post workshop survey that should be filled out. There&amp;#8217;ll be paper copies available, but filling it out online is quicker and&amp;#160;easier! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Pre-Workshop&amp;#160;Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Post-Workshop&amp;#160;Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve happened to stumble on this survey and &lt;em&gt;won&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; be attending the workshop, make my life a little easier and don&amp;#8217;t fill it out! &lt;em&gt;Note: these links are now dead, &amp;#8216;cus, uh, its&amp;#160;over.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Schedule&amp;#160;(theoretically)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:00&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Surveys!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:15&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Introductions (me, mostly)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9:30&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;How-to-make a Paper Speaker &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:20&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: red&#34;&gt;Break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:30&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Making circuits with Conductive Ink&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:30&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;A brief introduction to the ATTiny + TinyProgrammer (this might be ambitious)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:00&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Lunch &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Arduino-debugging&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:00&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Programming Blink. It&amp;#8217;s a miracle!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:15&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Programming TinySynth &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:30&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Code overview&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:45&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Make some Synths!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:10&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: red&#34;&gt;Break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:45&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fill out post-workshop survey&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;paper-speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paper&amp;#160;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve written up the basics, gleaned from many-a-resource,&amp;#160;here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/4/1/speaker-paperish&#34;&gt;Speakers&amp;#160;Paperish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://plusea.at&#34;&gt;Hannah Perner-Wilson&lt;/a&gt; is a one-person armada. She has done a variety of gorgeous&amp;#160;pieces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=1372&#34;&gt;Paper Speaker Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; at High-Low&amp;#160;Tech. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plusea.at/?p=4596&#34;&gt;Sea-shell&amp;#160;Headphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmarcelo.com/#/pulp-based-computing/&#34;&gt;Marcelo Coelho&lt;/a&gt; put together some particularly striking, insprirational examples, if a bit more involved than what we&amp;#8217;ll be&amp;#160;making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.karich.cl&#34;&gt;jckarich&lt;/a&gt; has a number of gorgeous projects (some done right at home, in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; Media Lab&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.karich.cl/?p=601&#34;&gt;Printed + Handmade&amp;#160;Headphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.karich.cl/?p=172&#34;&gt;Dollar Bill Ghetto&amp;#160;Blaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;templates&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;Templates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together a simple template, that guides you on how to make the design shown here, &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/2013/4/1/speaker-paperish&#34;&gt;Speakers Paperish&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s just a rough guideline, but can give you some&amp;#160;ideas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;tinyprogrammer&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;TinyProgrammer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TinyProgrammer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/11460&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TinyProgrammer is a sweet little tool that vastly simplifies the programming of Atmel&amp;#8217;s ATTiny45/85 microcontrollers. The ATTiny can do just about everything an Arduino can do (Atmel makes the ATmega168/32U4), but are much cheaper, smaller, and more easily embedded. If you want to make twenty of something, it&amp;#8217;s a lot easier to get your hands on 20 ATTinys (they&amp;#8217;re &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;$.95&lt;/a&gt; on SparkFun) than 20 Arduinos. &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.mit.edu/~mellis&#34;&gt;David Mellis&lt;/a&gt; designed this one. Or actually, he designed one, and SparkFun redesigned it to make it way&amp;#160;better.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started with it on your computer, you&amp;#8217;ll need (a) to have the Arduino &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt; installed (get it &lt;a href=&#34;http://arduino.cc/en/Main/Software&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you haven&amp;#8217;t already) and (b) have ATTiny installed (it doesn&amp;#8217;t come with the normal download). While the ATTiny is an Atmel chip (like the chips that power the Arduino), Arduino doesn&amp;#8217;t come with support for the ATTiny family out-of-the-box, so you&amp;#8217;ll have to follow the tutorial below to add ATTiny Support. Hopefully this&amp;#8217;ll change at some&amp;#160;point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=1695&#34;&gt;TinyProgrammer&amp;#160;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;tinysynth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;TinySynth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TinySynth is a program loaded onto an ATTiny45/85 that uses an eight-bit microcontroller to make sounds. We&amp;#8217;ll&amp;#160;need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TinyProgrammer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATTiny45/85&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coin&amp;#160;Cell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/posts/2013/4/1/speaker-paperish/&#34;&gt;Paper&amp;#160;Speaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conductive&amp;#160;Ink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting up and playing with the Tiny is simple enough. Most of the default Arduino sketches work with the ATTiny outt&amp;#8217;ve of the box. Some things will have to be tweaked, though, as the default Arduino pins don&amp;#8217;t necessarily map to anything useful on the Tiny&amp;#8212;pin 13, which by default is connected to an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; on an Arduino board doesn&amp;#8217;t go anywhere on a&amp;#160;Tiny:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;no-border&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/attiny45_85pinout.png&#34;/&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arduino-compatible pinout for Tiny45 (image courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=1695&#34;&gt;David Mellis&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program that we&amp;#8217;ll be loading onto our Tiny&amp;#8217;s is a basic sound generation library I&amp;#8217;ve written. You can peruse the source over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/tinysynth&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and down a .zip of the necessary files here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/tinysynth/archive/master.zip&#34;&gt;zip archive&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use, unzip the folder and open the &amp;#8220;tinysynth.ino&amp;#8221; file (you need to have Arduino&amp;#160;installed).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TinySynth has been preconfigured to have two touch-sensitive capacitive sensors and two LEDs, as well as a speaker output. See&amp;#160;below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8616341819/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4275 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8542/8616341819_38f4b4a9c7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4275&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;TOUCH1&lt;/code&gt; triggers &lt;code&gt;LED1&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TOUCH2&lt;/code&gt; triggers &lt;code&gt;LED2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;RESET&lt;/code&gt; pin is only used while the chip is being programmed. We could disable it, but it means that you&amp;#8217;d need some special hardware to ever program the chip again. &lt;code&gt;POWER&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GND&lt;/code&gt;, naturally enough, are connected to the positive and negative terminals of your power supply&amp;#8212;in our case, a coin-cell battery or&amp;#160;what-have-you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#8217;re programming the chip, we can test some of its functions &amp;#8212; but ultimately, we&amp;#8217;re going to making fancy-pants circuits outt&amp;#8217;ve of conductive ink. Below is a rough schematic of what the circuit looks like. The various symbols correspond to different components: batteries, LEDs, and so forth. Which is which? You&amp;#160;decide!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8623874872/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4304 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8256/8623874872_e352d6b6f1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4304&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your circuit doesn&amp;#8217;t need to look like this at all. These are just the&amp;#160;connections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying silver ink can be difficult. Go slow. With attention and care, you can draw fine, well-controlled&amp;#160;traces. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparing your microcontroller to work on a paper surface also requires some attention. Dave Mellis has put up some good, relevant guidlines here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=1653&#34;&gt;Micocontroller Circuit with Copper Tape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7976725337/&#34; title=&#34;Electric Narratives by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8440/7976725337_297dd84636.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Electric Narratives&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Painting with conductive silver&amp;#160;ink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The conductive silver ink we&amp;#8217;ll be using dries fairly slowly and was designed to be heat-dried at a specific temperature. A regular toaster oven will do the job. We&amp;#8217;ve supplied some hot-air stations and heateriziers that should work just as well. When working with microcontrollers, as we are, you need to be sensitive to the resistance of each line, because the microcontroller expects a very specific range of voltages on its&amp;#160;pins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a complete example with a big ol&amp;#8217; gramophone cone sticking out. This uses a painted silver speaker (instead of a wound-wire speaker), which works, but without amplification, is very&amp;#160;quiet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8465566076/&#34; title=&#34;Capactive touch button by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8233/8465566076_f70ec81291.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Capactive touch button&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speakers need to be coiled in a single direction&amp;#8212;so on the back of this sheet, there&amp;#8217;s a straight line leaving the&amp;#160;center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;battery-holder&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Battery&amp;#160;Holders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating &amp;#8220;hard&amp;#8221; components, like batteries and microcontrollers, with &amp;#8220;soft&amp;#8221; materials, like paper and textiles, is always difficult. Here&amp;#8217;s one way of creating battery a battery holder for a coin-cell battery, using the corner of a sheet of paper and a binder&amp;#160;clip. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fold over the corner of a sheet of paper. It should completely and easily cover the battery.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8623875732/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4311 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8522/8623875732_a2e2d02511.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4311&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using conductive ink, paint over the fold as shown in the black rectangles below. Because conductive paint doesn&amp;#8217;t crease well, it can sometimes be a good idea to replace those portions of your circuit with short lengths of copper tape (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10561&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;. The configuration has to be relatively precise, because you don&amp;#8217;t want to short the battery. Position it with the (+) side&amp;#160;up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8623875978/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4313 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8406/8623875978_d86d1c659b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4313&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fasten the folded over corner down over the battery with a binder clip.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8622772695/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4314 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8257/8622772695_aea218f794.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4314&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;mosfet&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Adding Amplification with a&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MOSFET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N-Channel &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MOSFET&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/NTD5867NL-1G/NTD5867NL-1GOS-ND/2401422?cur=USD&#34;&gt;DigiKey&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve made your circuit, you&amp;#8217;ll probably notice that it&amp;#8217;s not overwhelmingly loud. That&amp;#8217;s because we&amp;#8217;re driving the speaker with one of the pins of the microcontroller, which really isn&amp;#8217;t great for that sort of thing. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;#datasheet&#34;&gt;datasheet&lt;/a&gt;, the ATTiny can source about 20 milliamps, which isn&amp;#8217;t all that much. Using a &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MOSFET&lt;/span&gt;, we can drive a great deal more current through our speaker&amp;#8212;and theoretically at least&amp;#8212;make it&amp;#160;louder.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s my crude schematic of the mosfet that we&amp;#8217;ll be using. It has a particularly low threshold-voltage, which means it works well with the low-voltage coin-cell batteries. It&amp;#8217;s an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mosfet&#34;&gt;N-channel &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MOSFET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is very important, though why, I could not&amp;#160;say.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8623875122/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4305 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8530/8623875122_1e2968ca26.jpg&#34; width=&#34;485&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4305&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;G: Gate, D: Drain, S:&amp;#160;source&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out just how the &amp;#8220;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FET&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;as such things are sometimes called&amp;#8212;is hooked up into the circuit is trickier than it should be, at least for me. We&amp;#8217;re interested in the gate, drain, and source. The gate is what we&amp;#8217;ll connect to our microcontroller. The source, we&amp;#8217;ll connect straight to ground. And the drain, we&amp;#8217;ll connect to one end of our speaker. The diagram below gives about half the&amp;#160;answer.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8623875340/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4307 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8534/8623875340_6202ddab72.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4307&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missing piece, here, is what the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; end of the speaker is connected to. If one side is connected to drain &amp;#8212; the other side of your speaker should be connected to power. There are a variety of ingenious analogies that explain the way in which a &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MOSFET&lt;/span&gt; Works&amp;#8212;controlling a valve, opening and closing a dam&amp;#8212;but the more lucid ones escape me now. At any rate, suffice it to say, it allows the relative &lt;em&gt;weak&lt;/em&gt; microcontroller signal to control a much more powerful flow of current directly from the battery. Which naturally enough, makes it a bit more of a&amp;#160;ruckus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;helpful-information&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Helpful Links &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; So&amp;#160;Forth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=2505&#34;&gt;Copper Circuits&amp;#160;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technolojie.com/category/featured-projects/&#34;&gt;Jie Qi&lt;/a&gt; has put up some useful information about making circuits using copper tape on the High-Low Tech &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu/?p=2505&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;#8217;s also good information about the orientation of surface-amount LEDs&amp;#8212;which can be tricky to work&amp;#160;with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bareconductive.com/paper-battery-holders&#34;&gt;Bare Conductive&amp;#8217;s Paper Battery&amp;#160;Holder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really nice collection of elegant folded designs. Incorporating power into paper electronic projects has long been tricky, and these are some nice solutions. We&amp;#8217;ve long-used a binder clip and a coin-cell battery, which works pretty well&amp;#160;too.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;datasheet&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atmel.com/Images/Atmel-2586-AVR-8-bit-Microcontroller-ATtiny25-ATtiny45-ATtiny85_Datasheet.pdf&#34;&gt;ATTiny&amp;#160;Datasheet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not really that useful for our purposes here&amp;#8212;a hundred-odd pages of technical specifications. But it&amp;#8217;s interesting if you want to delve deeper into how people actually &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; these things. And the pin diagram is on the second&amp;#160;page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;it-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It&amp;#160;Happened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 6 &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; 7 has come and gone, and people put together many lovely things. Here&amp;#8217;s a handful:
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8632165003/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8386/8632165003_c487323eef.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8633287594/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8107/8633287594_fd4a18aca1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8633277890/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8246/8633277890_e6503a9163.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8632169749/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8522/8632169749_690ba4c5d1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8633278348/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8545/8633278348_eb150f37ff.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8633275918/&#34; title=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8243/8633275918_19d004bbd0.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Drawing the Electric Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">The Speaker Paperish</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/4/1/speaker-paperish"/>
        <updated>2013-04-01T22:08:02Z</updated>
        <published>2013-04-01T22:08:02Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/4/1/speaker-paperish</id>
        <summary type="html">In which audiophiles blanche.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8617159372/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-11 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8099/8617159372_74544320c3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After puttering along with carefully-crafted, if under-powered conductive silver speakers for a few weeks, an inquiring mind pointed me towards the small, cottage-industry of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DIY&lt;/span&gt; paper speakers using enameled magnet-wire (&lt;a href=&#34;http://https://www.sparkfun.com/products/11363&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;). They&amp;#8217;ve led a fairly fertile life online, courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.josepino.com/&#34;&gt;Jose Pino&lt;/a&gt;, who has put up a number excellent&amp;#160;projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve modeled these speakers, more-or-less, on his designs. See his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.josepino.com/science/howto-speaker&#34;&gt;Plastic Cup Speaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.josepino.com/?homemade-hifi-speaker&#34;&gt;Styrofoam Plate Speaker&lt;/a&gt; for some great &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;HOW&lt;/span&gt;-TOs. I haven&amp;#8217;t given the latter a try, yet, but it looks pretty&amp;#160;good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Paper&amp;#160;Speaker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bill of&amp;#160;Materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;30AWG&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;32AWG&lt;/span&gt; Magnet Wire (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/11363&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the stuff that gets wound into speaker coils and motors and such. You can grab it on eBay or naturally enough, Amazon, but SparkFun has a nice kit of it. You&amp;#8217;ll need more than you think. Sending an audio signal through these coils is what actually generates the magnetic field that moves the diaphragm, and ultimately, generates the&amp;#160;sound. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615956395/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings- 2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8101/8615956395_665b7dda85.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;393&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings- 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;This photo came out&amp;#160;funny.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnet (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcmaster.com/#5857K15&#34;&gt;McMaster&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Neodymium-Magnets-inch-Disc-N48/dp/B001KV38ES/ref=pd_cp_hi_2&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any kind of magnet works. The stronger the better. Keep in mind that whatever the shape of your magnet, for the best sound, that&amp;#8217;s going to be the shape of wire coil you&amp;#8217;ll be wrapping. So larger and rounder is better. You want a magnet (or) stack, taller than it is wide. I&amp;#8217;ve been using little rare-earth neodymium magnets, about ¼&amp;#8221; in diameter, which are admittedly a little small for a tube diameter. For those for whom mandatory overnight shipping is a way of life (be friends with me), McMaster has some nice &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcmaster.com/#5857K15&#34;&gt;ones&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8617060982/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings- 3 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8617060982_fd3a12a433.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;488&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings- 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The outer dimensions of the magnet will be (slightly-smaller) than the diameter of the paper&amp;#160;tube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stiff cardstock (A business card is pretty&amp;#160;good)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much anything works in pinch, but the sound will vary considerably with different materials. Apparently, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.josepino.com/?homemade-hifi-speaker&#34;&gt;foam plate&lt;/a&gt; is ideal. It&amp;#8217;s ugly,&amp;#160;though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elmer&amp;#8217;s is fine. Hot glue is faster. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615956029/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-1 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8259/8615956029_31773cd731.jpg&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;C&amp;#8217;est ne pas&amp;#160;glue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio Cable (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikey.com/product-search/en?x=-963&amp;amp;y=-71&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;site=us&amp;amp;KeyWords=CP-2207-ND+&#34;&gt;DigiKey&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t strictly necessary, but if you want to plug your speaker(s) into a proper computer or stereo or some such, you&amp;#8217;ll need something. The easiest thing to do, probably, is just cut-off a pair of old headphones or something. Then you&amp;#8217;ll get the &amp;frac18;&amp;#8221; jack, as well as a ground and left-and-right channel wire. You can do this with a blade if you&amp;#8217;re handy or a&amp;#160;wire-stripper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615957121/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-5 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8403/8615957121_990ebccc98.jpg&#34; width=&#34;469&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connect the alligator clips to the end of these&amp;#160;guys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alligator Clips, pair (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/11037&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For attaching to things: audio outputs, paper speaker wires, and so&amp;#160;forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615957463/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-5 1 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8380/8615957463_26b2c5f617.jpg&#34; width=&#34;492&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-5 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watch your&amp;#160;fingers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A speaker, essentially, is a coil of conductive material (wire, say, or conductive thread, or paint), and a permanent magnet. When a current flows through the coil, it generates a magnetic field. This field pushes or pulls itself against the &lt;em&gt;permanent&lt;/em&gt; magnet. If the flowing current describes sound, then the coil moves in ways that represent that sound. That&amp;#8217;s well and good, but so&amp;#160;what? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes a speaker a &lt;em&gt;speaker&lt;/em&gt;, and not just a bit of moving wire, is the diaphragm (read: business card), that is attached to the coil. As the card vibrates, it vibrates the air along with it. That air, my friend, that air is connected to other air, and that air vibrates too, until it vibrates right into your and your ear drum, from whence it does such mysterious things that probably, only &lt;a href=&#34;http://wikipedia.org/wiki/Ear&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea, here, is to create a paper tube that will move freely over the magnet, generating sound waves when audio is pumped through.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8617130356/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-10 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8388/8617130356_1bb318c9a8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;474&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this looks like a&amp;#160;cross-section&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut out the paper tubes. You should have two&amp;#8212;one taller than the other. You&amp;#8217;ll see&amp;#160;why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615958185/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-9 1 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8532/8615958185_3f04d84bab.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;234&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-9 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cut out the paper&amp;#160;tube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrap the paper tube around the magnet (or around a pencil, if your magnet is about that diameter). First wrap the taller tube. Then wrap the smaller. The larger tube will form a &amp;#8220;sleeve&amp;#8221; of sorts, that we&amp;#8217;ll discard. This&amp;#8217;ll give you the little&amp;#160;gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615958601/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-9 2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8546/8615958601_9b72bac762.jpg&#34; width=&#34;495&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-9 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wrap the larger tube around the magnet (or a pencil, if that&amp;#8217;s about the same&amp;#160;diameter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrap the enameled magnet wire around the smaller paper tube about fifty times. Strictly speaking, this number should vary with the particular wire and diameter you&amp;#8217;re using. As we&amp;#8217;re trying to build speakers that will work with a conventional headphone jack, if you have a multimeter around, we want a length that&amp;#8217;ll give us somewhere around 8Ω.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;impedance-mark&#34; href=&#34;#impedance-note&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8615957847/&#34; title=&#34;speaker-drawings-9 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8265/8615957847_afbd554c5e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; alt=&#34;speaker-drawings-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carefully wrap the magnet wire around the tube. It doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter how neatly you do&amp;#160;it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been smearing glue on the coil to fix it in place. Once you&amp;#8217;ve made your coil, it should look something like this:
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8614913386/&#34; title=&#34;Paper Speakers by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8381/8614913386_7b802f40cf.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Paper Speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used tape here, not glue. But glue is&amp;#160;better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, glue it to a business card. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8614912884/&#34; title=&#34;Paper Speakers by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8520/8614912884_ff500929f2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Paper Speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nifty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the ends of the wire are enameled, you won&amp;#8217;t be able to make good contact with the alligator clips. Use a bit of sandpaper, a blade, or&amp;#8212;I&amp;#8217;ve heard tell&amp;#8212;an &lt;em&gt;open flame&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting it altogether (and on some little paper legs, to let things flex, you&amp;#8217;ve got something that looks like&amp;#160;this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8618557853/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4285 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8393/8618557853_4643180b4d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4285&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The folded legs allow the business card to move up and down smoothly and&amp;#160;easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from the&amp;#160;top:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8619664614/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_4286 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8529/8619664614_46b1b3ea2e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_4286&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wires should be alligator clipped (or otherwise connected) to an audio output. One goes to ground, the other to the audio signal (either left or&amp;#160;right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should about do it. The speaker won&amp;#8217;t be very loud if you&amp;#8217;re driving it from your phone or computer. But try hooking it up to a proper amplifier and you should be able to make it &lt;em&gt;hop&lt;/em&gt;. Just be careful you don&amp;#8217;t melt your wires&amp;#160;down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve got it going, you can start elaborating on the basic&amp;#160;design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8614917764/&#34; title=&#34;Paper Speakers by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8122/8614917764_1c6db02a1a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Paper Speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plain &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;clean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8613809763/&#34; title=&#34;Paper Speakers by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8533/8613809763_3304daaa41.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Paper Speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the&amp;#160;reverse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8614918388/&#34; title=&#34;Paper Speakers by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8535/8614918388_5c8a5f9574.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Paper Speakers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bumping tunes through many superfluous&amp;#160;cones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a video where, to my eternal shame, I misspelled Gramophone (thanks, Madison, for the&amp;#160;catch!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/62743852&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;impedance-note&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1. &lt;p&gt;Most headphone jacks are actually looking for a higher-impedance load&amp;#8212;something like 16Ω&amp;#8212;but I&amp;#8217;ve never had a problem with lower values (as long as they&amp;#8217;re not too&amp;#160;low).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-note-number&#34; href=&#34;#impedance-mark&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                                                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Tracking Changes</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/1/31/tracking"/>
        <updated>2013-01-31T14:56:39Z</updated>
        <published>2013-01-31T14:56:39Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/1/31/tracking</id>
        <summary type="html">Because nothing happens all at once.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jsvine&#34;&gt;@jsvine&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; experiments in version-control at &lt;a href=&#34;http://drafts.jsvine.com&#34;&gt;drafts.jsvine.com&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I&amp;#8217;d expose some of the bones that tick beneath my &lt;a href=&#34;http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/21/hello-world/&#34;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;. I run these pages through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyde.github.com&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; static-site generator&amp;#8212;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; underloved Pythonic-cousin&amp;#8212;which despite being a little complex for the job, I&amp;#160;like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly use &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;github-1-mark&#34; href=&#34;#github-1-note&#34;&gt;†&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 as a glorified save button, not a collaborative tool (on this site at least)&amp;#8212;so all I needed to do was expose my changesets (already online on &lt;a href=&#34;http://https://github.com/samjacoby/samjacoby.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slapped together a small plugin that parses the logs of the repo that backs the site, and renders them on the page per-file in a reasonably-digestible manner. It would&amp;#8217;ve made more sense to be using mercurial (which is written in Python), but alas, GitHub is too damn&amp;#160;good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, you&amp;#8217;ll now see a &amp;#8216;Change History&amp;#8217; on the bottom of each page I&amp;#8217;ve worked on&amp;#8212;and if you&amp;#8217;re so inclined, can thumb-through my misspellings, fudged-dates, and all the rest.&amp;#160;Tantalizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plug-in, itself, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/hyde/commit/a92073bb46775499e1d510c2c71009ddd8101218&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in a not-very-palatable form. Pretty minimal, but you get the idea. The syntax-highlighting is a smidgen of&amp;#160;jQuery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;github-1-note&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;†. &lt;p&gt;My sister pointed out that &lt;em&gt;git&lt;/em&gt; looks suspiciously-like a typo for &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt;. It is not. Git is a popular piece of software that allows you to keep track of all of the edits you make on text files and easily collaborate and share your changes with others. While originally intended for software development, it&amp;#8217;s finding uses in a number of&amp;#160;projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-note-number&#34; href=&#34;#github-1-mark&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                                <entry>
        <title type="html">On Youth and Aquariums</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/1/10/rec-aquaria-misc"/>
        <updated>2013-01-10T09:16:43Z</updated>
        <published>2013-01-10T09:16:43Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2013/1/10/rec-aquaria-misc</id>
        <summary type="html">A first foray onto the internet.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been returning to aquariums with a force, lately, rigging-up a new set-up with a couple of neon tetras and a dozen-odd cherry chrimp that I picked up from Ebay.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;shrimps-1-mark&#34; href=&#34;#shrimps-1-note&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 I got started with aquariums years ago, in elementary school&amp;#8212;I don&amp;#8217;t recall why, exactly&amp;#8212;but perhaps it had something to do with growing up by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=allans+aquarium&amp;amp;aq=f&amp;amp;oq=allans+aquarium&#34;&gt;Allan&amp;#8217;s Aquarium&lt;/a&gt;, one of the finest fish stores&amp;#160;around.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, with aquariums on the mind, I dredged up my very first forays onto the &lt;em&gt;Internet&lt;/em&gt;. These are gems from the &lt;code&gt;rec.aquaria&lt;/code&gt; usenet, now archived on Google Groups. I remember posting these, sitting on my dad&amp;#8217;s lap on the dial-up that we had from&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UCLA&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a sample, posted in September of&amp;#160;1996:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My angel fish laid eggs.  What do I&amp;#160;do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam&amp;#160;Jacoby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell Jacoby (rja&amp;#8230;@ucla.edu) wrote:
My angel fish laid eggs.  What do I&amp;#160;do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam&amp;#160;Jacoby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy&amp;#160;cigars&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff&amp;#160;Walther &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9/18/96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&amp;#160;Jeff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest, on subjects as diverse as lighting levels and fungus,&amp;#160;follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/topic/rec.aquaria/DSWy2pzS4LY/discussion&#34;&gt;A First&amp;#160;Query&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/topic/rec.aquaria.misc/yJEnYgB5UMo/discussion&#34;&gt;Help!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/topic/rec.aquaria.misc/VoCg5tQCt78/discussion&#34;&gt;My Angelfish Laid&amp;#160;Eggs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/topic/rec.aquaria.freshwater.cichlids/Wra8_VF8Elg/discussion&#34;&gt;Yep, they laid&amp;#160;eggs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/rec.aquaria.misc/CaYx1yE6-e4/XrIiAwaTupYJ&#34;&gt;Now the eggs have&amp;#160;fungus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/rec.aquaria.misc/GKtTqKJRugM/q90fAIm2u6AJ&#34;&gt;Those babies are swimming&amp;#160;around&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/topic/rec.aquaria.freshwater.plants/h6JJXePrZgo/discussion&#34;&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t keep my plants&amp;#160;alive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/rec.aquaria.misc/BFA8Cz-d-GM/i5uN5yqADKcJ&#34;&gt;I got some&amp;#160;frogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;shrimps-1-note&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1. &lt;p&gt;Shipped for 12 bucks from Florida, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USPS&lt;/span&gt; priority. Arrived alive and kicking. A bit of a miracle in the heart of&amp;#160;winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-note-number&#34; href=&#34;#shrimps-1-mark&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Amazon EC2 Microinstances</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/12/9/amazon-ec2"/>
        <updated>2012-12-09T19:36:01Z</updated>
        <published>2012-12-09T19:36:01Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/12/9/amazon-ec2</id>
        <summary type="html">Succumbing to the siren song of the cloud.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In which my adventures in migrating some small-websites over to Amazon&amp;#8217;s vaunted services are&amp;#160;discussed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;To those who have much, yet&amp;#160;more.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I&amp;#8217;ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services (&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;. Now, I&amp;#8217;ve been a spectacularly satisfied customer of &lt;a href=&#34;http://asmallorange.com&#34;&gt;A Small Orange&lt;/a&gt; for years,  but I&amp;#8217;ve been lately frustrated by the limitations of shared hosting. As I play around with different application platforms (Rails, Django, NodeJS), as part of my continuing professional-development-program, its clear that I need a bit more than &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;250MB&lt;/span&gt; of space and a restricted shell.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:service&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:service&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, over this weekend, I migrated my sites over to play around with the twelve-months free access provided for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt; micro-instances, that is, tiny cheap servers. It&amp;#8217;s been reasonably enlightening. I&amp;#8217;ve built up a couple of &lt;code&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/code&gt; images, my preferred distribution, and played with getting environments spinning up for some &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/monotype-app&#34;&gt;applications&lt;/a&gt; that haven&amp;#8217;t seen the light of day in some&amp;#160;time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;To Cloud. Or not to&amp;#160;Cloud?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some part of me&amp;#8212;or well, most of me&amp;#8212;dislikes the cloud. Yes, it&amp;#8217;s convenient. Yes, Amazon, Rackspace, and all the rest do a damn-good job of things. Yes, it&amp;#8217;s the future. Virtual machines are great, make sense, are cheap, effecient, and all the rest. In some way, though, it&amp;#8217;s equal parts exciting and depressing&amp;#8212;there is something lost and something gained, when you spin up an instance from yet-another &lt;code&gt;dashboard&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always found something striking about that bit of magic that comes with connecting a run-down beige box to an ethernet port in the corner of a room, configuring its permissions, and having it flash its small payload across the waves. This &lt;em&gt;cloud&lt;/em&gt;, for all the hoopla&amp;#8212;is just better word off-site refrigerated storage with 24-hour access. Convenient, sure. But like gmail, you&amp;#8217;re trading convenience for freedom. As much as &lt;code&gt;AWS&lt;/code&gt; is convenient, it&amp;#8217;s also inherently less-free. Amazon&amp;#8217;s got your&amp;#160;stuff.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, ever the modern man,  I am a pragmatist&amp;#8212;and even if I won&amp;#8217;t remain with Amazon forever, I thought I should start figuring out how some their systems work. And what can I say? Right now, I have an insanely-fast, scalable, reliable, customizable server, with root access. I can&amp;#8217;t really&amp;#160;complain.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I&amp;#8217;ve got two micro-instances running&amp;#8212;one is serving the static pages, the other, a little &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/monotype-app&#34;&gt;typography training app&lt;/a&gt; I wrote a few years ago. That won&amp;#8217;t last long, because you only get one instance free&amp;#8212;but I&amp;#8217;ll switch the nameservers back to &lt;code&gt;A Small Orange&lt;/code&gt; soon, while continuing to serve the dynamic content from&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reverse&amp;#160;Proxies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;#8217;ve long heard preached that fine practice&amp;#8212;the prudent splitting of dynamic and static content. That makes plenty of sense, really. Or plenty of sense if I ever had much content to serve. In practice, though, It&amp;#8217;s not something I&amp;#8217;ve ever needed. As someone who has only ever placed things online from some reptilian instinct to share, I have never had any problems with server performance&amp;#8212;to say the least. For some time, I ran my personal website from an X40.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:X40&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:X40&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a million-and-one ingenious ways to do this and I don&amp;#8217;t understand half of them. All I wanted was a nice, static server that put pages that I made on the internet, and two, have another server throw up some of the dynamic content. That way, I could have one clean server&amp;#8212;where I actually knew what was going on&amp;#8212;and pass off all of the messy stuff to other computers that had whatever intricate combination of python and everything else that was&amp;#160;necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter reverse proxies&amp;#8212;which are exactly what they sound like. When you ask for something from a server, it scurries of to yet &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; server, and fetched it from there, passing it through itself and onward to you. So you never know that what you asked for came from some other place. And the proxying server doesn&amp;#8217;t have to worry itself about whatever complex things you asked for, fobbing you off on some other machine (in my case, the correct &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt; instance). Reverse proxies are what really pushed me to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt;, ultimately, as they&amp;#8217;re not allowed in the shared hosting environment of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:option&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:option&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, they&amp;#8217;re dead simple. These are what mine look&amp;#160;like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ProxyPass /apps/monotype/ http://ec2-109-21-77-32.compute-1.amazonaws.com/monotype/&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ProxyPassReverse /apps/monotype/ http://ec2-109-21-77-32.compute-1.amazonaws.com/monotype/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exciting stuff, eh? Never done anything easier. Now, I&amp;#8217;m not doing any of the fancy load-balancing or the various bells and whistles that real people probably do, but it&amp;#8217;s been a pleasant introduction. The Apache docs give the rather stern warning: make sure you don&amp;#8217;t inadvertently turn your server into a &lt;em&gt;forward&lt;/em&gt; server, in which case it can be easily hijacked and redirected to all sorts of nefarious&amp;#160;ends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Serving Images from&amp;#160;S3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added 2015-08-06 10:25:09&lt;/em&gt;
I&amp;#8217;ve used Flickr&amp;#8217;s lovely embedded iframes to serve most of the images on this site, but lately, I&amp;#8217;ve been frustrated with how slowly it loads. On some of the image heavy pages on my &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/motorcycle/&#34;&gt;motorcycle&lt;/a&gt; project, it&amp;#8217;s very noticeable. I don&amp;#8217;t think the slideshow format works well for this site, anyhow, so I wanted to look into how to do my image hosting with &lt;code&gt;s3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:s3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:s3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to change my own development habits, though, so I turned to my &lt;code&gt;.htaccess&lt;/code&gt; file, which my host, &lt;a href=&#34;https://asmallorange.com/&#34;&gt;ASmallOrange&lt;/a&gt;, respects, even though I&amp;#8217;m in a super-cheap shared &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;VPS&lt;/span&gt; with very limited shell&amp;#160;access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;RewriteCond&lt;/span&gt; %{REQUEST_FILENAME} !-f
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;RewriteCond&lt;/span&gt; %{REQUEST_FILENAME} \.jpg$ 
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;RewriteRule&lt;/span&gt; ^.*media\/img\/(.*)$ https://s3.amazonaws.com/Shackman/samjacoby.com/$1 [L]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it! In the &lt;code&gt;fabfile.py&lt;/code&gt; that I use to manage the deployment of this website, I also added the&amp;#160;following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;local&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;aws s3 sync --delete --exclude &amp;#39;.DS_Store&amp;#39; --acl=&amp;#39;public-read&amp;#39; --size-only deploy/media/img/ s3://Shackman/samjacoby.com/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;aws&lt;/code&gt; utility is provided by Amazon—and while the sync function is not as clever as rsync, it works well enough for my&amp;#160;purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:service&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, this isn&amp;#8217;t &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ASO&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s problem. They&amp;#8217;ve been absolutely wonderful. I have never interacted with a company&amp;#8212;not in tech, not anywhere, with more respnsive customer service. I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ve had a ticket go unresponded to for more than fifteen minutes. And I pay $25-a-year for the privilege.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:service&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:X40&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, after realizing that it would be a royal pain-in-the-ass to have mod_wsgi compiled against python3, while having some virtualenvs that were still using Django 1.3 &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Python 2.6 and so on&amp;#8230;absolute misery.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:X40&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:option&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are surely some clever ways around this, perhaps using RewriteRule and permanent redirects. A quick scan shows that this is indeed the case, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/current/rewrite/flags.html#flag_p&#34;&gt;[P] flag&lt;/a&gt; passes requests through to mod_proxy.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:option&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:s3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, the entire site is static, so it could all be served from s3, but whatever.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:s3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Sliders &amp; Wheels</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/wheels-and-sliders"/>
        <updated>2012-12-09T19:36:01Z</updated>
        <published>2012-12-09T19:36:01Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/wheels-and-sliders</id>
        <summary type="html">Sketching more complex interface elements using soft graphite.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I headed over to Utrecht Art Supply earlier today to act on a hunch that I&amp;#8217;ve had for awhile. They&amp;#8217;ve got a nice selection of writing and drawing tools, and I picked up a variety of very, very soft graphite pencils. I didn&amp;#8217;t even know they went up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pencil_hardness#Grading_and_classification&#34;&gt;9B&lt;/a&gt;, but there it was&amp;#8212;a gleaming rod of solid graphite. It had a nice heft to it, too. I got a range of hardnesses and headed back to the&amp;#160;lab. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphite is reasonably conductive, which means that you can do all kinds of neat things with pencils. Jay Silver paved the way with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.media.mit.edu/~silver/drawdio/&#34;&gt;Drawdio&lt;/a&gt;, a beautiful project that grafts analog sound-generation onto an ordinary #2. I&amp;#8217;ve had some trouble getting the kind of consistent conductivity that I need, though, to make some of the sensors I&amp;#8217;m interested in&amp;#8212;at least without tediously going over and over the same&amp;#160;lines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8265296707/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8060/8265296707_cbffe6b474.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;2900 9B, be still my heart. Smudged with my&amp;#160;finger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a regular pencil, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;HB&lt;/span&gt;, say, there&amp;#8217;s a fair amount of clay mixed in with the graphite to stiffen it up. That allows the tip to hold a thinner line and last longer, but naturally-enough, reduces its conductivity. With the 9B pencil, however, I found that I could make much more reliable lines in just a pass or two. Old news, probably, but fun to play&amp;#160;with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So-equipped with my quiver of new acquisitions, I started sketching out some of the interfaces that I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about with my &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/tapclip/&#34;&gt;TapClip&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;project.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first indication that things were working nicely. This line had a resistance of around 2 MΩ, which is fine for my purposes. The clip was triggering nicely, though the line is probably a foot-and-a-half long, at least. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8266365010/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8077/8266365010_8f6c179ac8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quick line, sketched out. TapClip is attached at the&amp;#160;back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you slide your finger across sliders of this form, you create stronger electric field with one narrow slice and then another. By interpolating between those signals, you can accurately determine where exactly your finger is. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8265297671/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8349/8265297671_8c9cacb040.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interdigitated&amp;#160;slider.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capacitive sensing works through most substrates (like the glass in your phone, for example)&amp;#8212;so as far as it&amp;#8217;s concerned, you can use the sensor through the back of sheet. That&amp;#8217;s nice for two reasons: first, you can draw whatever you&amp;#8217;d like on top, and second, actually &lt;em&gt;touching&lt;/em&gt; a capacitive sensor turns it into a resistive sensor, which can be a good (but complicating) thing.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8265298379/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8478/8265298379_bcdc7561d6.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;And flipped over, (thanks for the tip, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.media.mit.edu/~mellis/&#34;&gt;@mellis&lt;/a&gt; so you can draw whatever you want on the reverse. Works&amp;#160;perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is essentially that same slider, but bent into a wheel shape. It took some doing to come up with an algorithm that could accurately track your finger as it moves around the circle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8266366662/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8058/8266366662_91db216dc2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capacitive&amp;#160;wheel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a graph generated by a little script, that plots the signals from each portion of the wheel over time. If you look closely, you can see the signal passing smoothly from one capacitive region to the other.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8266400874/&#34; title=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8216/8266400874_8d885c7d4d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;484&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Graphite Sliders &amp;amp; Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graph of scrolling over the wheel. Notice that the peaks are slightly&amp;#160;offset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">A Visit to the MIT Glass Lab</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/12/4/glass-lab-at-mit"/>
        <updated>2012-12-04T17:05:59Z</updated>
        <published>2012-12-04T17:05:59Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/12/4/glass-lab-at-mit</id>
        <summary type="html">High-Low Tech goes on a field trip. Hi-jinks ensue.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;A venture-some crew headed down to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/glasslab/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; Glass Lab&lt;/a&gt; last week for a demonstration of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caneworking&#34;&gt;caneworking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Glass Lab is something apart at &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;. Less lasers, more 15th-century Italian glassblowing. I&amp;#8217;d assumed that it was a hold-over from the days when chemistry departments blew their own glass and the like, but I believe it comes from the materials&amp;#8217; science department, or some such. There is a much coveted lottery every semester, where a lucky dozen or-so get a chance to learn the craft. I&amp;#8217;ve missed every opportunity,&amp;#160;alas.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8252047247/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8063/8252047247_dbf63a22e6.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gang,&amp;#160;skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/glasslab/peeps_pbhouk.html&#34;&gt;Peter Houk&lt;/a&gt; presented some of his work to &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;High-Low Tech&lt;/a&gt; a couple of months ago&amp;#8212;and then invited us back over to his place to experiment with some new software that &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtualglass.org/team.html&#34;&gt;Erik Demaine&lt;/a&gt;, among others, have been working on. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtualglass.org&#34;&gt;Virtual Glass&lt;/a&gt;, essentially a &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CAD&lt;/span&gt; tool that lets you experiment with different configurations of &lt;em&gt;cane&lt;/em&gt; (colored glass rods) and see how the cane will appear once pulled. I don&amp;#8217;t know if &amp;#8220;pulled&amp;#8221; is the technical term, but that&amp;#8217;s what it seemed like to me. Making glass has a lot in common with pulling taffy and baking&amp;#8212;at least in these early&amp;#160;stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8252050527/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8067/8252050527_b8093028b8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;White and red cane&amp;#8212;probably six-or-eight inches long&amp;#8212;awaiting a pick-up on a glass&amp;#160;plug.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erik gave us a quick demo&amp;#8212;though the software is fairly self-explanatory, especially after you&amp;#8217;ve seen the cane made&amp;#8212;and we came up with a number of designs of varying degrees of practicality. The point, really, was to push the designs as far as we could go&amp;#8212;and see what kind of things Peter, Marty, &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Erik could put together. This is what I came up&amp;#160;with: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter was pushing us to make &amp;#8216;unconventional&amp;#8217; designs, as the last innovations in cane configurations were by an Italian dentist a half-century ago. It&amp;#8217;s harder than it might seem. Because the hot glass is twisted as it is pulled into cane, patterns converge very quickly on helices, no matter how loopy your layout. The only real tool you have, then, as a designer, is the distance of each color each color from the&amp;#160;center. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8253121374/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8065/8253121374_f649ef3764.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtualglass.org&#34;&gt;Virtual Glass&lt;/a&gt; software and my squiggly&amp;#160;design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a piece of hot glass is pulled out and spun&amp;#8212;I&amp;#8217;m sure this process has a lovely Italian name that I don&amp;#8217;t know&amp;#8212;the colors are stretched in concordance to how far they are from the center. Colors near the center of the cane show hardly any rotation at all&amp;#8212;a vague waver, maybe. Those towards the edge wrap around dramatically, pulled around the entire circumference. In using a spiral design, the distance of the various canes from the center of the larger cane varied in a way that seemed pretty&amp;#160;cool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8252050895/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8488/8252050895_964870d1d5.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fearsome flame&amp;#160;fires.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, Team Glass Lab decided to make it happen. There was only about a half-hour, so time was tight. It was quite a show. In corner one, we&amp;#8217;ve got dual furnaces, each heating a white-hot pool of glass. In corner two, a glory-hole, an insanely-hot furnace in which dabs of glass are reheated and heated when on the end of an uh&amp;#8230;punty? I may have made that term up&amp;#8212;a long metal rod, at any rate. A blowtorch is off in the corner, braying its firey mess. (For some additional anthropological thoughts on the subject, please see: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;ved=0CDgQFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.scasss.uu.se%2FIIS2005%2Ftotal_webb%2Ftot_html%2Fpapers%2Fembodied_knowledge.pdf&amp;amp;ei=mR7CUPSeOLGG0QHL0IHICA&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEurTuRIijIgxjSkvYBr88V9uoA7g&amp;amp;sig2=OtTGICr3kqIYG77wUhMrdQ&#34;&gt;Conner, Erin, Embodied Knowledge in Glassblowing: the experience of meaning and the struggle towards proficiency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I read this paper for a class on qualitative ethnography last year. Smutty&amp;#160;stuff.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8253115392/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8208/8253115392_20b5c1662a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something critical taking&amp;#160;place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching Peter, Eric, &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Marty work was impressive. They zipped around, waving flaming gobs of glass, while we gawked and generally got in the way. In the end, they managed to make the design that we came up with. It was intricate, involving bonding together several different pieces of cane in a variety of ways, and then dousing the resultant mess in yet more glass. Something like making an elaborate, deadly,&amp;#160;pastry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wish this was in focus, but alas. This is molten glass being stretched out. Peter&amp;#8217;s on one end, Marty the other. By the time it hardened, they&amp;#8217;d gotten it up to probably 30 feet&amp;#160;long. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8253114588/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8209/8253114588_29474548e1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;299&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cane being pulled. You can see the dyes in the glass radiating their&amp;#160;heat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished cane came out pretty cool too, though I think, more subtle than we had hoped. This is part of the end, that they let me take home after it had annealed. The finished cane&amp;#8212;even, pencil-long sticks&amp;#8212;will be used in blowing a larger, finished&amp;#160;piece.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8252044655/&#34; title=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8347/8252044655_5e42c65c15.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;172&#34; alt=&#34;High-Low Tech visits the MIT Glass Lab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ooooo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Words I&#39;ve Looked Up</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/11/21/words-ive-looked-up"/>
        <updated>2012-11-21T21:49:03Z</updated>
        <published>2012-11-21T21:49:03Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/11/21/words-ive-looked-up</id>
        <summary type="html">So that I could know them and remember them in my heart.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;This is a list of words I&amp;#8217;ve looked up for one reason or&amp;#160;another. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=abscissa&#34;&gt;abscissa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=agonist&#34;&gt;agonist&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=affiance&#34;&gt;affiance&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=apposite&#34;&gt;apposite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=agora&#34;&gt;agora&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=apophenia&#34;&gt;apophenia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=armamentarium&#34;&gt;armamentarium&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=asemic&#34;&gt;asemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=boondoggle&#34;&gt;boondoggle&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=boustrophedon&#34;&gt;boustrophedon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=captious&#34;&gt;captious&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=cathexis&#34;&gt;cathexis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=chiliastic&#34;&gt;chiliastic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=conspectus&#34;&gt;conspectus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=copacetic&#34;&gt;copacetic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=cucumbrously&#34;&gt;cucumbrously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=cynosures&#34;&gt;cynosures&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=descant&#34;&gt;descant&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=demotic&#34;&gt;demotic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=ectomorph&#34;&gt;ectomorph&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=écorché&#34;&gt;écorché&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=enuresis&#34;&gt;enuresis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=entablature&#34;&gt;entablature&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=epicaricacy&#34;&gt;epicaricacy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=epicene&#34;&gt;epicene&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=escutcheon&#34;&gt;escutcheon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=friable&#34;&gt;friable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=gimcrackery&#34;&gt;gimcrackery&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=heretofore&#34;&gt;heretofore&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=Herzogian&#34;&gt;Herzogian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=homoiconicity&#34;&gt;homoiconicity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=hoydenish&#34;&gt;hoydenish&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=inapposite&#34;&gt;inapposite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=indempotent&#34;&gt;indempotent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=kinesthesia&#34;&gt;kinesthesia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=kinesthesis&#34;&gt;kinesthesis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=kinesthetic&#34;&gt;kinesthetic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=nictate&#34;&gt;nictate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=lagniappe&#34;&gt;lagniappe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=lavaliere&#34;&gt;lavaliere&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=luculent&#34;&gt;luculent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=neurasthenia&#34;&gt;neurasthenia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=numinous&#34;&gt;numinous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=obloquy&#34;&gt;obloquy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=oneiric&#34;&gt;oneiric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=paludarium&#34;&gt;paludarium&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=pantile&#34;&gt;pantile&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=pareidolia&#34;&gt;pareidolia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=pataphysics&#34;&gt;pataphysics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=pelisse&#34;&gt;pelisse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=peregrination&#34;&gt;peregrination&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=pablumpetrichor&#34;&gt;pablumpetrichor&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=plenary&#34;&gt;plenary&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=plethoric&#34;&gt;plethoric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=phlebotomy&#34;&gt;phlebotomy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=polysemy&#34;&gt;polysemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=prefatory&#34;&gt;prefatory&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=propaedeutic&#34;&gt;propaedeutic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=proprioception&#34;&gt;proprioception&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=proscenium&#34;&gt;proscenium&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=prosopagnosia&#34;&gt;prosopagnosia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=protean&#34;&gt;protean&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=puissant&#34;&gt;puissant&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=quisling&#34;&gt;quisling&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=radix&#34;&gt;radix&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=replete&#34;&gt;replete&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=saccade&#34;&gt;saccade&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=scrying&#34;&gt;scrying&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=seriatim&#34;&gt;seriatim&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=shambolic&#34;&gt;shambolic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=suplex&#34;&gt;suplex&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=untrammeled&#34;&gt;untrammeled&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=vassalage&#34;&gt;vassalage&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=verruca&#34;&gt;verruca&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ninjawords.com/?q=vinculum&#34;&gt;vinculum&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Hidden Layers</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/11/15/hidden-layers"/>
        <updated>2012-11-15T18:37:09Z</updated>
        <published>2012-11-15T18:37:09Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/11/15/hidden-layers</id>
        <summary type="html">In which I am screwed by layers in Eagle.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The journey continues. This is part of my work as a research assistant in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlt.media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;High-Low Tech&lt;/a&gt; group at the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; Media&amp;#160;Lab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the design that I drew the board up from. Looks pretty good, right? Well, I was happy: lot&amp;#8217;s of complicated little parts, colors&amp;#8212;enough for me to feel like I was doing my&amp;#160;job.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8233965024/&#34; title=&#34;Screen shot 2012-11-30 at 6.55.07 PM by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8062/8233965024_7826261394.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;445&#34; alt=&#34;Screen shot 2012-11-30 at 6.55.07 PM&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;An&amp;#160;electro-rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent off the gerber files, and had another board made by the good men and women of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt; Circuits. They did bang-up job, naturally. I was walking around the lab with them, and Mark said, &amp;#8220;That from &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt; Circuits?&amp;#8221; You can spot one of these gems from across the room&amp;#8212;it&amp;#8217;s in the fancy-pants solder mask, apparently. Whatever the reason, you can spot one of these gems from across the room: circuit bling. I happily toasted it&amp;#160;up.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8233964610/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_2281 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8340/8233964610_036da21ae3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2281&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s 246&amp;#160;&amp;#8451;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finished board, bristling with muxes and PGAs and all the rest. Looks pretty&amp;#160;good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8232901503/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_2299 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8350/8232901503_68b725bb1b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2299&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;StoryClip = TapClip =&amp;#160;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, some of the savvier among you may note that there are substantial errors in this circuit. To you, I tip my hat. I was&amp;#160;oblivious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, our hero is plugging the board into his computer, ready to bask in the radiance of its green, power&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. Poke around a bit. Nothing. Pull out the multimeter. Could there be a bridge in thin traces of the mini-&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; connectior? No. 5V streaming in. That looks good. But, hmm, streaming out? Ah&amp;#8230;well, not so much. And then I see it. None of the grounds are connected. Only one half of my circuits are&amp;#160;routed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the story. It&amp;#8217;s not so grand. At some point in the development process, I did something bad. To simplify my design, I used a ground plane&amp;#8212;a single sheet of copper that the ground of all of the traces plugged into. After &amp;#8220;pouring&amp;#8221; the ground (kind&amp;#8217;ve like the fill tool in paint, or something), the screen was looking a little crowded. I turned off its display. Great. In so doing, though, I also turned off the airwires&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;airwires-mark&#34; href=&#34;#airwires-note&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 that it came with. Naturally, I then promptly forgot I did any such thing and proceeded on my merry way. Getting the board made and all the&amp;#160;rest.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, though, the job wasn&amp;#8217;t really done. The pouring algorithm had done its job, sure&amp;#8212;but it had left a number of sections for me, it&amp;#8217;s human-companion to resolve. The groundplane needed a number of additional airwires that I never added back in. My circuits, then, were a series of orphans, plugged into nothing but themselves! I needed &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt; additional wires. I was&amp;#160;crushed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, lesson learned. Don&amp;#8217;t switch off views and think you&amp;#8217;ve solved any problems. You&amp;#160;haven&amp;#8217;t.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;airwires-note&#34; class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1. &lt;p&gt;Airwires are just a wire that you&amp;#8217;re supposed to solder on later, so it&amp;#8217;s displayed as a single line in Eagle. That&amp;#8217;s all well and good and sometimes a well-placed airwire can take care of a number of problems&amp;#8212;but they&amp;#8217;re difficult and tedious to solder, and really, if you&amp;#8217;re having a custom-board made, you should take care not to have&amp;#160;any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-note-number&#34; href=&#34;#airwires-mark&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">Experiments in Etching</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/etching-experiments"/>
        <updated>2012-10-25T10:55:11Z</updated>
        <published>2012-10-25T10:55:11Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/etching-experiments</id>
        <summary type="html">In which lasers are used wrong.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been vaguely attending a printmaking class at Harvard. I can&amp;#8217;t say I&amp;#8217;ve commited myself, but I have learned the rudimentary basics of etching. Now, with a standard etching, you use a scraper or scribe or pointy nail, or whatever, really, to scratch away at a coating applied to smooth sheet of copper (or zinc, in this case). Those scratches expose the bare metal, which you &amp;#8220;etch&amp;#8221; (ah &lt;em&gt;hah!&lt;/em&gt;) in an acid bath. You fill the resulting grooves with ink, wipe off the rest, mash some paper down, and there you go. That&amp;#8217;s all well and good. After all, it&amp;#8217;s how Dürer, Rembrandt, Picasso, and some other famous dudes made it happen. But since we&amp;#8217;ve got a lot of toys to play with at the Media Lab, it seems a shame not to use&amp;#160;them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I finally got round to running some experiments with the laser cutter and hard-ground that I&amp;#8217;ve been meaning to get&amp;#160;to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123812594/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8463/8123812594_18d89dae73.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of&amp;#160;circles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used some simple Processing code to generate the shapes (at least, the circles and the spiral), and burned the resulting designs into zinc plates, before etching them normally. I was skeptical, initially, because it appeared that the laser had not burned down to the bare metal&amp;#8212;and even a thin layer of ground would prevent the acid from doing its work. That didn&amp;#8217;t appear to be a problem, though, once I dipped them in the nitric acid. Even so, I wasn&amp;#8217;t convinced until I actually pulled a print. They came off surprisingly&amp;#160;nicely.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I daubed out a few of the artifacts that were left in the ground from its various journeys from Harvard to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt; and back, but left most of the them (you can see the aphaltum in the nitric acid&amp;#160;bath).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123795757/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8051/8123795757_2707bc86c1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spiral. The scratches are just from the ground being worn off in the course of jouncing around inside of my&amp;#160;bag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123813022/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8334/8123813022_b6062aa779.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Triangle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The natural variation in the brush-applied ground varied the intensity of the etched&amp;#160;line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123792895/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8194/8123792895_f2ef084faf.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying the hard ground as&amp;#160;normal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123811112/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8466/8123811112_07f9e3f67d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laser-etching a simple design into the&amp;#160;ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I was concerned that the laser-burned line had not reached the zinc layer, you can see from the bubbles developing on the metal&amp;#160;surface.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/8123793935/&#34; title=&#34;Experiments in Etching by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8186/8123793935_f74473c2fe.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Experiments in Etching&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;After some touch-ups, dipping the sucker in nitric acid. It stings a&amp;#160;little.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Moving&amp;#160;on&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the laser cutter was surprisingly unpredictable. The uneven nature of the hard ground meant that the laser melted through it somewhat irregularly, skipping areas with relatively more ground. The combination of hand-work and machine-guided precision is something I&amp;#8217;d like to play around with more. Something definitely be worth experimenting with is the use of other ground materials that might give different results in the laser&amp;#160;cutter. &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Reports from the City</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/10/1/maker-faire"/>
        <updated>2012-10-01T09:06:55Z</updated>
        <published>2012-10-01T09:06:55Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/10/1/maker-faire</id>
        <summary type="html">Tales from MakerFaire NYC &amp; OSHW.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;h3&gt;Open Source Hardware&amp;#160;Summit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recuperating this week from a grand time in New York City. We converged on its gray shores last week to stop by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://summit.oshwa.org/&#34;&gt;Open Source Hardware Summit&lt;/a&gt;, where people vaguely gesticulated in the direction of &amp;#8220;open source&amp;#8221; and show-cased their projects. The good men (and they are that) of &lt;a href=&#34;http://drinkicd.com&#34;&gt;Industry City Distillery&lt;/a&gt; were there, handing out thimbles of&amp;#160;vodka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;World MakerFaire &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NYC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;2012&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I made the sojourn out to Flushing. I&amp;#8217;ll reserve the tale of our trevails on the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; for another day&amp;#8212;suffice it to say, it took two-and-half hours to stumble out to the hinterlands of Queens and I barely arrived in time for a workshop on conductive ink with &lt;a href=&#34;http://colloids.matse.illinois.edu/group.html&#34;&gt;Analisa Russo&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#8217;d brought a number of her pen-on-paper conductive silver pens (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;sqi=2&amp;amp;ved=0CB0QtwIwAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DdfNByi-rrO4&amp;amp;ei=vzpsUJ-kCOLs0gGU44A4&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFuKfDJmQer68cq6NDkMcaGRU8JOA&amp;amp;sig2=plpSOvME2xkO7-n3zvTUOw&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;) to play&amp;#160;with.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was racing about, so didn&amp;#8217;t get a chance to snap many photos&amp;#8212;but things turned out nicely. Many thanks to AnnMarie Thomas and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://makered.org&#34;&gt;Maker Ed&lt;/a&gt; team for making it&amp;#160;happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8050299166/&#34; title=&#34;MakerFaire 2012 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8029/8050299166_c5b2621596.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;MakerFaire 2012&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Getting underway.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8050300272/&#34; title=&#34;MakerFaire 2012 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8035/8050300272_2993168c4e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;MakerFaire 2012&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Amanda &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; her masterpiece.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8050294519/&#34; title=&#34;MakerFaire 2012 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8033/8050294519_9b48827426.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;MakerFaire 2012&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Check out the close-up. Look at those traces!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8050295033/&#34; title=&#34;MakerFaire 2012 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8451/8050295033_c65438711e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;MakerFaire 2012&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Nice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8050301920/&#34; title=&#34;MakerFaire 2012 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8177/8050301920_6797fb209d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;MakerFaire 2012&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;We&amp;#8217;re doing science on the 7 train. No one thought this was weird.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                        <entry>
        <title type="html">99 Fridays &amp;amp; IR Throwies</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/9/26/99-fridays"/>
        <updated>2012-09-26T10:08:23Z</updated>
        <published>2012-09-26T10:08:23Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/9/26/99-fridays</id>
        <summary type="html">The little guys hit the big time.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the inestimable efforts of &lt;a href=&#34;http://colorsaregood.com/index.php&#34;&gt;Valentin Huen&lt;/a&gt;, we pulled together a whopping &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/ir-led/throwies/&#34;&gt;500 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; Throwies&lt;/a&gt; for the Media Lab&amp;#8217;s latest 99 Friday dance-party &lt;em&gt;cum&lt;/em&gt; project-showcase. I use &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8221; rather loosely: I was racing against a conference paper deadline, so Valentin heroically recruited a small army of people to scale up the &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/ir-led-throwies/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; Throwies&lt;/a&gt; project. It came off pretty&amp;#160;well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8070857656/&#34; title=&#34;IR Throwies by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8177/8070857656_764138f70f.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;334&#34; alt=&#34;IR Throwies&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;500 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; Throwies under construction (photo courtesy of Valentine&amp;#160;Huen).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a batch that I tested with an Arduino and an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; light array. The array&amp;#8212;it turned out&amp;#8212;wasn&amp;#8217;t the right wavelength, so though the response was good in the comfort of my office, once we were trying to blanket an entire space, it didn&amp;#8217;t work all that well. Valentin scrounged up some of the right LEDs though, and that worked fine. &lt;em&gt;Then&lt;/em&gt; we had some issues with the receiver&amp;#8217;s error-detection and noise-rejection &amp;#8212; but managed to get around it with some jerry-regging. The morial is what it always is: read the datasheet. Once things were squared away, the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; transmitter was synced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://bdm.cc&#34;&gt;Brian&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OSC&lt;/span&gt; stream that distributed levels and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FFT&lt;/span&gt; bands to whomever was listening to the server. When the emitter pulsed, the LEDs pulsed-with. Not bad. Even figured out some nice &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PWM&lt;/span&gt; action,&amp;#160;too.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8070864153/&#34; title=&#34;IR Throwies by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8315/8070864153_93b8a8f089.jpg&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;IR Throwies&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before they&amp;#8217;ve been attached to clothespins and all. Testing&amp;#160;functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the final batch. Each throwie was attached to a clothespin so that people could attach them to their clothes. I wish I had some shots from the actual party, with everyone dancing and all, but I had to take off once we had them working to entertain a very patient, out-of-town guest. I heard that they were a hit&amp;#160;though.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/8070863365/&#34; title=&#34;IR Throwies by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8180/8070863365_2225c127b7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IR Throwies&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final lot, brought up to the party and triggered by the&amp;#160;music.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a bad showing, all in all. And cheap &amp;#8212; though it starts to add up in&amp;#160;quantity. &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">TapClip v.2</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/9/8/en-masse"/>
        <updated>2012-09-08T12:06:17Z</updated>
        <published>2012-09-08T12:06:17Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/9/8/en-masse</id>
        <summary type="html">Onwards and upwards. Building a gang of touch-sensitive boards.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;In preparation for a workshop last weekend&amp;#8212;I populated the ten bare-bones boards I&amp;#8217;d picked up from Advanced Circuits (see my last &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/2012/8/31/building-boards/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;). I&amp;#8217;ve done a bit of this now, but with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bdm.cc&#34;&gt;Brian&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; ever-essential help, I got really cruising. The ten boards probably took about an hour with a few&amp;#160;hiccups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979858673/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7979858673_da2b664fa8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Applying solder paste, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://resenv.media.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;ResEnv&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; pneumatic machine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;resenv.media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;Responsive Environments&lt;/a&gt;, my dear friends and partners in electro-crime, have an extraordinarily well-equipped electronics &amp;#8220;pen&amp;#8221;. This syringe is connected to an automatic pneumatic dispenser with accompanying footpedal&amp;#8212;so you can squeeze out a regular bead of solder paste. This is a &lt;code&gt;QFP&lt;/code&gt; package&amp;#8212;so not the smallest out there&amp;#8212;but pretty damn small.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979858073/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8456/7979858073_28324ed031.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Throwing down Atmel 168s&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
There&amp;#8217;s also a vacuum lift (I don&amp;#8217;t know what they&amp;#8217;re really called)&amp;#8212;but it&amp;#8217;s a mechanical arm that helps you place the chips accurately. Sort&amp;#8217;ve like a manual pick-and-place. Actually, that&amp;#8217;s exactly what it is. Handy.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979859099/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8299/7979859099_cddc37be65.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Toasting the solder paste under hot air &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
Once all of the components are down, I ran them through the hot-air soldering/rework station&amp;#8212;which streams a jet of balmy 260&amp;deg;C air over the boards and melts the solder. It&amp;#8217;s pretty cool to watch. As the solder liquefies, it beads up on the pad and lifts the passive components into alignment. So as you run the boards through, as they heat-up, they wiggle into alignment. This can be an issue&amp;#8212;apparently&amp;#8212;with smaller components (like &lt;code&gt;0402s&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;0201&lt;/code&gt;s) which are small enough to be bodily lifted off their pads by the solder ball and &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dataweek.co.za/news.aspx?pklnewsid=11343&#34;&gt;tombstone&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#8221;
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979860065/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8303/7979860065_3f42ee5d14.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Soldering on the alligator clips by hand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
Large components need to be soldered by hand. These are the alligator clips for fastening the board to a piece of paper.They&amp;#8217;re fairly large so take a bit to heat up.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979860409/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8299/7979860409_43e0bd82bb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;377&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Programming boards with an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AVR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
A nice little trick: you don&amp;#8217;t have to actually solder on an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; header if you have plated vias on your board. You can just hold the headers in the holes. Works pretty well&amp;#8212;though I would solder something on if I were debugging.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7979860214/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8436/7979860214_e33a23c620.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;A small army&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
Hey, not a bad&amp;#160;team.&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Building Boards</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/31/building-boards"/>
        <updated>2012-08-31T10:33:23Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-31T10:33:23Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/31/building-boards</id>
        <summary type="html">Whipping together some quick prototype circuit boards.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;My circuit board order came in &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s always astonishing how tiny the things are, these boards are about the size of two postage stamps, side-by-side. The &amp;#8220;barebones&amp;#8221; option from Advanced Circuits is a pretty good deal too. These cost $8.90 apiece, which is pretty reasonable. I know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://apccircuits.com&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;APC&lt;/span&gt; Circuits&lt;/a&gt; has really quick turn-around for boards with solder mask and such, but I didn&amp;#8217;t need it. I&amp;#8217;m mostly proud for remembering not to pour a groundplane, as it makes it a pain to solder. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7900310464/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0359 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8318/7900310464_b9102dd273.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0359&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nice &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; pretty&amp;#160;like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a bunch of &lt;code&gt;0603&lt;/code&gt; resistors to provide the loads on the capacitive pads (those rectangles along the top). Those suckers are small. What&amp;#8217;s all the more astonishing, is that there is yet a &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; size, 0402, which is about the size of a grain of sand. And Brian was telling me that some special-purpose boards can have the passive elements like those baked right into the various&amp;#160;layers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7900311646/&#34; title=&#34;0603 Resistor by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8310/7900311646_930af5efac.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;0603 Resistor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resistor + Finger. Mostly&amp;#160;finger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to catch a flight out to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8212;though it was delayed 2 hours&amp;#8212;but I managed to throw together a board to bring with, so I could do some work on the plane (of course, I ended up not doing any). After puzzling for a minute why the &lt;code&gt;FTDI&lt;/code&gt; programming only worked the first time after burning the Arduino bootloader, I realized that I hadn&amp;#8217;t put in the auto-reset capacitor between the &lt;code&gt;DTS&lt;/code&gt; pin of and the &lt;code&gt;RST&lt;/code&gt; line. It works the first, because the bootloader itself holds the chip in reset (thanks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.media.mit.edu/~mellis/&#34;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7900312620/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.2 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8321/7900312620_42e83107db.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am still learning about&amp;#160;f-stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soldered on the toothless alligator clips today (what gems! [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newark.com/silvertronic/502008/toothless-steel-alligator-clip/dp/82R5349&#34;&gt;Newark&lt;/a&gt;]) and drew up an aquatic sketch to have some examples to show folks for the workshop I&amp;#8217;ll be&amp;#160;doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7929989432/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0426 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8451/7929989432_54a77a2a56.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0426&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the&amp;#160;sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">PaperClip</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/29/paperclip"/>
        <updated>2012-08-29T11:37:24Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-29T11:37:24Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/29/paperclip</id>
        <summary type="html">Designing a touch-sensitive sensor + sound-sample recording software.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on the software for TapClip&amp;#8212;which is rolling along, in preparation for a workshop next week. So far, it&amp;#8217;s working pretty well, though the &lt;code&gt;minim&lt;/code&gt; library is causing me some grief. There appears to be a noticeable lag-time when using &lt;code&gt;loadSample&lt;/code&gt; to queue a &lt;code&gt;.wav&lt;/code&gt; file in&amp;#160;memory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it has something to do with this &lt;code&gt;buffer underrun&lt;/code&gt; error I&amp;#8217;ve been seeing a lot of (see below). It&amp;#8217;s thrown somewhere in the &lt;code&gt;javasound&lt;/code&gt; library, and I haven&amp;#8217;t tracked it down yet, so that&amp;#8217;s all I&amp;#8217;ve got. At any rate, it&amp;#8217;s probably not that important (the error, I mean)&amp;#8212;but if I can&amp;#8217;t get it resolved, I may give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tree-axis.com/Ess/&#34;&gt;Ess&lt;/a&gt; library a try (thanks to Nick Gillian of &lt;a href=&#34;http://nickgillian.com&#34;&gt;NickGillian.com&lt;/a&gt; for the&amp;#160;suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/Processing/tree/master/TapClipSound&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/media/img/scaled_paperclip-processing.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Gerber File Extensions</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/24/gerber-file-extensions"/>
        <updated>2012-08-24T22:42:58Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-24T22:42:58Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/24/gerber-file-extensions</id>
        <summary type="html">Making sense--mostly--of the alphabet soup of circuit board layout files.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Lest anyone be misled, &lt;strong&gt;this is a post about making circuit boards.&lt;/strong&gt; Thrilling&amp;#160;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I send off Gerbers for production, I am baffled by the array of files that the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CAM&lt;/span&gt; job in Eagle generates. I&amp;#8217;m happy to be ignorant. That&amp;#8217;s fine. The issue is, when you upload your files to most board fabs, they cheerily list the half-dozen odd things you&amp;#8217;ve sent them&amp;#8212;and ask you what they are? Top solder mask? &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NC&lt;/span&gt; drill file? I know nothing of this. So&amp;#8212;some research later, and this is what we&amp;#8217;ve&amp;#160;got.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of my knowledge&amp;#8212;using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4mypcb.com&#34;&gt;Advanced Circuits&lt;/a&gt;, these are the file extension mappings using the Eagle Gerber &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;RS274X&lt;/span&gt; cam file. I may have once changed the default extensions randomly a few months ago&amp;#8212;so handle with care. There are some inconsistencies as detailed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.protoexpress.com/content/gerber_extensions.jsp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. A nice summary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.uml.edu/~fredm/courses/91.548-spr03/eagle-gerber-output.shtml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well. Thanks,&amp;#160;Fred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, we&amp;#8217;ll see how the boards come&amp;#160;out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.cmp&lt;/strong&gt; / top&amp;#160;copper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.drd&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NC&lt;/span&gt; drill from&amp;#160;excellon.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.dri&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; an &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NC&lt;/span&gt; drill file. Do we need both? I don&amp;#8217;t know. Probably not. But someone told me to generate the excellon paths once, so I&amp;#160;do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.plc&lt;/strong&gt; / top&amp;#160;silkscreen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.sol&lt;/strong&gt; / bottom&amp;#160;copper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.stc&lt;/strong&gt; / top solder&amp;#160;mask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.sts&lt;/strong&gt; / bottom solder&amp;#160;mask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.gpi&lt;/strong&gt; / screw this one. General board info. Not&amp;#160;needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Using Arscons</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/24/arscons"/>
        <updated>2012-08-24T14:10:22Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-24T14:10:22Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/24/arscons</id>
        <summary type="html">Free&#39;d from the kind tyranny of the Arduino IDE.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a post about me &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; my computer. Get&amp;#160;excited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Arch Linux &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Thinkpad X40: A love&amp;#160;story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve used Arch Linux for years &amp;#8212; always a bit ineptly, I must admit &amp;#8212; and a while back, mostly because of a new job (and the allure of ditching my open-source sensibilities and using Adobe &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt;), I switched to a Mac. I&amp;#8217;ve been happy enough, but there&amp;#8217;s something about coding in Snow Leopard or Lion or Cat or whatever we&amp;#8217;re on, that I&amp;#8217;ve never really liked. Too slick, maybe. I find I work better in heavily constrained&amp;#160;environments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve always had another machine around for my &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; coding work. That lot falls to an old Thinkpad X40 that I hauled around on a six-month jaunt in Nicaragua, when I was taking some time off from college and working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://ticotimes.net&#34;&gt;The Tico Times&lt;/a&gt;. I was running Ubuntu then. It was like a rock&amp;#8212;it&amp;#8217;s still going strong. Over the years, I&amp;#8217;ve amassed a small armada of X40s: you can get one in working-order on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.com/sch/Laptops-Netbooks-/175672/i.html?_nkw=x40%20thinkpad&amp;amp;_mPrRngCbx=1&amp;amp;_udlo=10&amp;amp;_udhi=76&#34;&gt;Ebay&lt;/a&gt; for under $65 bucks. How can you&amp;#160;resist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Arch +&amp;#160;Arduino&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my latest X40, I&amp;#8217;m running Arch off&amp;#8217;ve a charming &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;4GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; stick (the X40s on Ebay are almost always stripped of their hard-drives). It&amp;#8217;s a little pokey, particularly on writing to disk, but I couldn&amp;#8217;t be happier. And my little, cranky, skull-bucket of a Thinkpad feels as roomy as the glossy 13&amp;#8221; MacBook Pro I usually work and the keyboard has none of the mushy play. (Read up on Mako&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://mako.cc/copyrighteous/20111207-00&#34;&gt;great post&lt;/a&gt; on the great swindle that is the 16:9 screen ratio &amp;#8212; which is why the X40 &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; actually as large as the&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MBP&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, all of that doesn&amp;#8217;t change the fact that it&amp;#8217;s an antiquated machine and I use it primarily for text editing. Not much else. I like coding on it&amp;#8212;there&amp;#8217;s no electro-peace like a tiling windows manager (Awesome) and someone else&amp;#8217;s fantastic&amp;#160;.vimrc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://bdm.cc&#34;&gt;Brian Mayton&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; Makefile (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/avr/blob/master/makefiles.templates/avr_makefile_brian&#34;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt;) to compile my avr programs&amp;#8212;but honestly, I love the convenience of the Arduino libraries and all the rest, even if they&amp;#8217;re anathema to Assembly&amp;#160;Cowboys. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not growing up on embedded programming, the whole &lt;code&gt;(1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; PB4)&lt;/code&gt;, alas, does not quite feel like first nature. One sore spot has been the Arduino &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt;, which in all its muscular Java-ness, is a bit much for the X40 to&amp;#160;handle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8212;how do you use the Arduino libraries in the comfort of your own &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; config? There are a couple of ways. I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/suapapa/arscons&#34;&gt;Arscons&lt;/a&gt;, a python build script, that makes the process relatively&amp;#160;painless. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install the&amp;#160;necessaries: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codehilite&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pacman&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;python&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pyserial&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;scons&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then grab the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/suapapa/arscons&#34;&gt;SConstruct&lt;/a&gt; file and copy it into your sketch folder. Run &lt;code&gt;scons&lt;/code&gt;, and let the magic unfold. Maybe. Didn&amp;#8217;t work for me outt&amp;#8217;ve the box. Because I have several versions of avr-gcc, a conflict prevented programs from compiling correctly. I edited the SConstruct file to make it work right&amp;#8212;in my case, I just modified the &lt;code&gt;AVR_BIN_PREFIX&lt;/code&gt; setting to point to the actual Arduino install of &lt;code&gt;avr-gcc&lt;/code&gt;. That broke &lt;code&gt;avrdude&lt;/code&gt;, but such is life. I don&amp;#8217;t know exactly what was amiss, but it seemed to have worked&amp;#160;fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#8217;s that&amp;#8212;not so grand. Scons is basically Make&amp;#8212;or does the same things, at least&amp;#8212;and lets you use Python rather than all of that gibberish. There &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Makefiles&lt;/code&gt; for Arduino that do the exact same thing&amp;#8212;but they are even more of a code&amp;#160;soup.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; I checked in with Dave and Arduino ships with its own version of avr-gcc with a number of necessary&amp;#160;tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NOTE&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, yes, I know I can use an external editor with Arduino, but I don&amp;#8217;t like doing that for some reason. I end up being confused about where I should be&amp;#160;editing. &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Touch Tiny v.1</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/22/touch-tiny-under"/>
        <updated>2012-08-22T20:49:40Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-22T20:49:40Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/22/touch-tiny-under</id>
        <summary type="html">Playing with capacitive sensing in a tiny way.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;h3&gt;Parts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atmega32u4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AT42QT1070&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AT42QT11110&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to be doing a quick layout to test out the various QTouch chips&amp;#8212;which Leah has warned me, work little-better than the code we&amp;#8217;ve got running on plain old ATtinys (which is what the QTouch chips are,&amp;#160;basically). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll also have some pads straight to the 32u4 to test out the CapSense library&amp;#8212;and our custom code, as&amp;#160;well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also going to do a smaller version with an ATtiny44&amp;#8212;actually, I think I&amp;#8217;ll do that one first, just so I can quickly mill out a board and see how the alligator clips behave with the conductive ink and all the&amp;#160;rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Parts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATtiny44&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AVR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;Header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;FTDI&lt;/span&gt; 6-pin&amp;#160;header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six toothless alligator&amp;#160;clips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to scrap all that, and make a version that uses an Atmega 168&amp;#8212;like an Arduino&amp;#8212;as that&amp;#8217;s the version that I&amp;#8217;m most familiar with. Here&amp;#8217;s the board layout I scrapped together. Works ok, though I ultimately ended up milling one with a resonator.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7851854616/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.1 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7118/7851854616_89997de2df.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; alt=&#34;TapClip v.1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7854691568/&#34; title=&#34;TapClip v.1 in action, by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7275/7854691568_7b0a4e936b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0328&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">TapClip</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/tapclip"/>
        <updated>2012-08-22T12:57:30Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-22T12:57:30Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/tapclip</id>
        <summary type="html">A capacitive-sensing board for creating ad-hoc computer interfaces from conductive inks.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a project that brings together a broad set of my research at&amp;#160;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TapClip is a specialized capactive sensor board that I&amp;#8217;m using as a test-bed for exploring ad-hoc user-interface design, and more broadly, self-made&amp;#160;technologies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s served as a platform, both for &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/storyclip/&#34;&gt;StoryClip&lt;/a&gt;, as well as SynthClip below, which is a self-contained musical interface, running a simple 8-bit wave generation algorithm. Each clip was associated with a specific set of tones, which it cycled through automatically. Pressing multiple clips blended their sounds together. This would be a good place to have an mp3 or something.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:mp3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:mp3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/synthclip-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only you could hear it&amp;#8217;s 8-bit&amp;#160;purring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TapClip, as a general concept, shares much with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeymakey.com/&#34;&gt;Makey Makey&lt;/a&gt;. Jay &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Eric worked just downstairs from me at the Media Lab, and I stole every idea I could find. The key difference is simply in the basic use-case. The Makey Makey is designed to emulate a keyboard, so works in tandem with a computer. This opens up a series of sophisticated interactions that take full-advantage of a computer&amp;#8217;s horsepower (and internet connectivity). That moves the focus of interaction from the computation itself, to the materiality of the conductive substrate. That, and technically, TapClip relied on a series of simple two-pin capacitive sensors, rather than the resistive pins in the Makey&amp;#160;Makey. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Eagle files are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/Eagle/tree/master/TapClip32u4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also documented some of my process in a variety of briefer posts. Take a&amp;#160;look.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:mp3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope. &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:mp3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Hello, World.</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/21/hello-world"/>
        <updated>2012-08-21T13:24:28Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-21T13:24:28Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/posts/2012/8/21/hello-world</id>
        <summary type="html">In which I greet you, gentle reader.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;With some consternation, I&amp;#8217;ve overhauled my&amp;#160;website. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much is due to the fine work of &lt;a href=&#34;http://stevelosh.com&#34;&gt;Steve Losh&lt;/a&gt;, whose work I&amp;#8217;ve assiduously cribbed, both in web design, &lt;code&gt;.vim&lt;/code&gt; configs, and much&amp;#160;else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyde.github.com/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;, which is complex enough to make me feel smart, and simple enough to be actually useful. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://goldengridsystem.com&#34;&gt;Golden Grid System&lt;/a&gt; gave me all of the nifty &amp;#8220;Responsive Web&amp;#8221; tricks for free. Fun fact: I helped put Ethan Marcotte&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abookapart.com/products/responsive-web-design&#34;&gt;e-book&lt;/a&gt; together for &lt;a href=&#34;http://abookapart.com&#34;&gt;A Book Apart&lt;/a&gt; back when I worked for&amp;#160;Threepress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for this website is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samjacoby/samjacoby.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Not much to see, but knock yourself out if you&amp;#8217;re so&amp;#160;inclined. &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Infra-Red LED Throwies</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/ir-led-throwies"/>
        <updated>2012-08-16T10:54:13Z</updated>
        <published>2012-08-16T10:54:13Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/ir-led-throwies</id>
        <summary type="html">Use an ordinary remote control to blink LED throwies on and off.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been toying with with ideas for a quick, easy, scalable project for a large group of teenagers to do together for the Boston &lt;a href=&#34;http://icaboston.org&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ICA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; Teen&amp;#160;Night. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always really liked the little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/LED-Throwies/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; Throwies&lt;/a&gt; from the fine people over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://graffitiresearchlab.com/&#34;&gt;Graffiti Research Lab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; here&amp;#8217;s an updated version that allows for the little guys to be controlled by a regular old remote control. It&amp;#8217;s a little startling how simple the whole operation&amp;#160;is.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7735310028/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0203 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8287/7735310028_7885198dbc.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0203&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking&amp;#160;alright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Material&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we need: not much. If you&amp;#8217;re interested, I drew up a &lt;a href=&#34;/media/files/ir_throwie.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; hand-out&lt;/a&gt; that details some of&amp;#160;this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CR2032&lt;/span&gt; Battery [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/CR2032/P189-ND/31939&#34;&gt;DigiKey&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what lives inside of millions of watches, all over this fine land. And what keeps the time in your computer accurate, and a bunch of other things. You can get them&amp;#8212;for a small fortune&amp;#8212;at a drugstore. Someone told me that Ikea was now selling them at close to wholesale&amp;#160;prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Regular &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/533&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/C503B-BCS-CV0Z0461/C503B-BCS-CV0Z0461-ND/1922944&#34;&gt;DigiKey&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much anything like this will do. Available at RadioShack, Sparkfun, or wherever fine, finger-friendly electronics are&amp;#160;sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;38KHz Infrared Receiver [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10266&#34;&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digikey.com/scripts/dksearch/dksus.dll?vendor=0&amp;amp;keywords=751-1390-5-ND&#34;&gt;Digikey&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what makes the magic happen. There are a number of these out there&amp;#8212;the frequency, 38KHz, is an industry-standard&amp;#8212;so anything like that should work fine. This model has worked well for me and I tried a handful. These are more or less the little fellows that live inside of your &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, or radio, or anything, really, that&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; remote-controlled. Look for ones with&amp;#160;three-legs.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnet&amp;#160;(optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8216;classic&amp;#8217; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; throwie has a magnet, so it can be chucked at anything metal and will stick. Certainly, you can do the same with this. I didn&amp;#8217;t, but you certainly&amp;#160;could. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scotch&amp;#160;tape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For wrapping the whole shebang&amp;#160;together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote&amp;#160;Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any one should do. I just grabbed one for a television that was lying&amp;#160;around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784243140/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0333 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7127/7784243140_9383a38a50.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0333&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step&amp;#160;1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bend the legs of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; Receiver and of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; apart, so that they can span the battery easily:
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;section class=&#34;side-by-side&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784243814/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1186 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7261/7784243814_f91ef8501e_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1186&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
    &lt;section class=&#34;side-by-side&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784244454/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1199 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8440/7784244454_31ced29ae5_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1199&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step&amp;#160;2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the &lt;em&gt;ground&lt;/em&gt; pin of &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8212;the shorter one&amp;#8212;and the &lt;em&gt;out&lt;/em&gt; pin of the receiver (if you use the same model that I did, it&amp;#8217;ll be on the left when the &amp;#8220;domed&amp;#8221; part is facing you), and twist them firmly together. Don&amp;#8217;t be shy. Twist em&amp;#8217;. You can always redo it. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784245022/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1237 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8435/7784245022_467246ebf6.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1237&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step&amp;#160;3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to throw that battery in there. That means connecting up the legs, to the &lt;em&gt;positive (+)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;negative (-)&lt;/em&gt; sides of the battery. Hold your&amp;#160;breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;postitive (+)&lt;/em&gt; lead of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8212;that is, the long one&amp;#8212;and the &lt;em&gt;positive (+)&lt;/em&gt; lead of the receiver&amp;#8212;the one on the middle&amp;#8212;should touch the &lt;em&gt;positive (+)&lt;/em&gt; side of the battery. There should be a user-friendly &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; on the battery to help you out with that, but you shouldn&amp;#8217;t burn anything if you do it&amp;#160;wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784245772/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1250 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8298/7784245772_92aac85b3d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1250&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something, of course, needs to head to the back of the battery, to the &lt;em&gt;minus (-)&lt;/em&gt; side to complete the circuit. Both legs of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; are busy&amp;#8212;so take the free leg of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt; Receiver&amp;#8212;the on the far right&amp;#8212;and bend it around to the back and hold it against the battery. Make sure that it doesn&amp;#8217;t make contact with anything&amp;#160;else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold that sucker tight with your fingers. You&amp;#8217;re pretty much done. If you&amp;#8217;ve got a remote handy, now&amp;#8217;s the time to point it at your gizmo and press a button to make sure you&amp;#8217;ve got it figured right. &lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt;?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trouble?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing works for the first time. That&amp;#8217;s just a&amp;#160;rule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try a couple buttons if the first one doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to work&amp;#8212;depending on the remote, some modes might be disabled (say, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; guide buttons when you&amp;#8217;re in cable-mode) and your remote won&amp;#8217;t be firing. Then check that all of your leads (legs) are doing what you think they&amp;#8217;re doing and connected where you think they&amp;#8217;re connected, and that you haven&amp;#8217;t inadvertantly shorted anything&amp;#8212;say, across the lip of the&amp;#160;battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you feel good about the operation, wrap it all up in tape &amp;#8212; and you&amp;#8217;re ready to throw-in a magnet, integrate it into a project, or whatever. It starts getting really good when you put together a couple hundred of these, which will all blink synchronously when you fire off. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784246988/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1293 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/7784246988_26ecbed8db.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1293&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 4 //&amp;#160;Rejoice.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s like a &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;. A one-pixel &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/40358770@N00/7784247614/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1262 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8283/7784247614_41aa4e6f8c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;380&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1262&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">Paper Sensors</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/paper-sensors"/>
        <updated>2012-05-04T19:19:10Z</updated>
        <published>2012-05-04T19:19:10Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/paper-sensors</id>
        <summary type="html">Experiments in conductive ink: strain gauges &amp; accelerometers.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;The idea, here, was to recreate some basic &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MEMS&lt;/span&gt; sensors using paper &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; conductive&amp;#160;ink. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The raw materials. A bit of silver ink&amp;#8212;this stuff, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://conductivecompounds.com&#34;&gt;Conductive Compounds&lt;/a&gt;, a mysterious organization up in New Hampshire&amp;#8212;a brush, and a laser-cut stencil. I designed the circuit in Eagle, though that was just for my own amusement.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195054272/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0047 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7093/7195054272_cd1f697de5.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0047&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The modern&amp;#160;scientist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the &amp;#8220;right&amp;#8221; way to do it, is to screen-print it, but I am lazy. Dabbed on a bit through the stencil, which I&amp;#8217;d tacked down with some spray adhesive. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195055646/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0067 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7079/7195055646_3aa5ff5b99.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0067&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worked about&amp;#160;half-the-time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Strain&amp;#160;Gauge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design is based on the work of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_M._Whitesides&#34;&gt;George Whitesides Lab&lt;/a&gt;, who have done a lot of fine work in paper electronics. Actually, they&amp;#8217;ve done most of the work in paper electronics. Pretty good stuff. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195061592/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0133 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7240/7195061592_7814160473.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0133&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strain gauge, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.utep.edu/li/images/PDFs/2011%20paper%20mems%20loc.pdf&#34;&gt;Paper-based piezoresistive &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MEMS&lt;/span&gt; sensors, Liu et&amp;#160;al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black stripe is carbon-based ink, which has a far higher resistivity than the silver stuff, and changes resistivity dramatically when flexed. The components are attached with conductive epoxy, which works pretty well. You can speed the drying process along by throwing it in a toaster&amp;#8212;you can see the baked lines on this guy. I left it in too long. Worked fine. When cured, the ink goes down to something like 0.3Ω/cm. Not&amp;#160;bad.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an early test of just the paper gauge. It seems a little lagged, but I think that&amp;#8217;s just because I did a bad job syncing the videos&amp;#8212;and because of the latency inherent in the flex of the paper.
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/54917926?badge=0&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/54917926&#34;&gt;Paper Strain&amp;#160;Gauge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package just has four op-amps, each boosting up the signal to a different level. The blue blocks are adjustable potentiometers, to equalize the legs of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wheatstone_bridge&#34;&gt;Wheatstone Bridge&lt;/a&gt;, making the gauge damn sensitive.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195059934/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0120 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5155/7195059934_aa410efe80.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0120&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Op-amp at the heart of the strain-gauge, doing some fine&amp;#160;work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Paper&amp;#160;Accelerometer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accelerometer works on a totally different principle, and a lot of the fanciness isn&amp;#8217;t embedded on the page&amp;#8212;though there is a transimpedance amplifier, in there, which converts the voltage on one plate into current, allowing for the flexing of the little paper tab to be picked&amp;#160;up.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a pretty crude accelerometer and works pretty well when you blow on it too. No word on durability. I&amp;#8217;d guess, not very. 
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195067476/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0242 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8149/7195067476_53f7b06897.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0242&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accelerometer. Or anemometer, for that&amp;#160;matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the scope picks up on the other side. The square is wave is being sent out of a microcontroller (an Arduino)&amp;#8212;and you can see the inverted signal coming through on the opposing plate. By shaking the accelerometer, the voltage of the induced signal changes&amp;#8212;it&amp;#8217;s larger when the two plates are closer. A current is only induced when the voltage is &lt;em&gt;changing&lt;/em&gt;, though, which is why there are only spikes when the square wave is changing. That gives you a crude metric of motion&amp;#8212;hence, the &lt;em&gt;accelerometer&lt;/em&gt;. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t say it&amp;#8217;s all that reliable or repeatable, though.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;with-caption&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7195065918/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_0193 by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7100/7195065918_b428d221b5.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_0193&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scope. First row is the transmission wave. Second is the induced (post-amplification)&amp;#160;voltage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the ever-generous &lt;a href=&#34;http://bdm.cc&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;BDM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for helping make this&amp;#160;happen.&lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">English Monotype Game</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/monotype-app"/>
        <updated>2010-10-09T14:20:34Z</updated>
        <published>2010-10-09T14:20:34Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/monotype-app</id>
        <summary type="html">How well do you know your classic humanist typefaces?</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/media/img/monotype-composite-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garamond, Joanna, &lt;span class=&#34;amp&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#160;Centaur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fine printing community, there is a slight kerfuffle around the aesthetic difference between type designed for letterpress printing and type designed for digital or offset printing. With the rise of photopolymer printing, many designers are using digital-native typefaces to print on film, which inevitably results in bulky, inelegant letterforms, as a digital type design doesn&amp;#8217;t account for the cross-sectional distribution of&amp;#160;ink-on-paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first typefaces adapted for phototypesetting and digital printing were, as a rule, too light and too spindly. They were also, generally, somewhat malformed. While high-quality metal typefaces were cut slightly differently at various sizes&amp;#8212;so 18 pt. Bembo was not simply a scaled up facsimile of 10 pt. Bembo (or vice versa), but somewhat elaborated upon&amp;#8212;digital typefaces had no such&amp;#160;subtlety.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, this is all a very long way of saying, one of the first Django projects I put together was a little typography-training game. Rather than using digital copies of the typefaces, though, I scanned each letter-form from a specimen book of English Monotype that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://katranpress.com&#34;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; let me borrow. Other than that, there&amp;#8217;s not that much to it. &lt;span class=&#34;strike&#34;&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t had this hosted live in awhile, but I recently started looking into Amazon Web Services, which made setting up an &lt;code&gt;ec2&lt;/code&gt; instance a&amp;#160;snap.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;strike&#34;&gt;At any rate, try your hand: &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Classic Typefaces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;I killed the instance, as it was too expensive to keep running after my free year. Thought I&amp;#8217;d use it for other things too, but mostly use Heroku now. Anyhow, it&amp;#8217;s damn old&amp;#160;now.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
                <entry>
        <title type="html">A Desk That I Made</title>
        <link href="http://samjacoby.com/projects/a-desk"/>
        <updated>2010-07-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <published>2010-07-20T12:00:00Z</published>
        <id>http://samjacoby.com/projects/a-desk</id>
        <summary type="html">A home-brewed desk for desk-related purposes.</summary>
        <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;One week at summer&amp;#8217;s end, I decided I should have desk. No glue. No screws. One piece of 4 &amp;times; 8&amp;#8242; birch-veneered plywood. It&amp;#8217;s kept tense by the tight-fitting angled notches that hold the boards together&amp;#8212;though the cables in the back don&amp;#8217;t&amp;#160;hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some crude &lt;a href=&#34;#plans&#34;&gt;plans&lt;/a&gt; are&amp;#160;below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/media/img/scaled_desk-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/media/img/scaled_desk-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/media/img/scaled_desk-3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans&#34;&gt;Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basic first-sketch that I followed. A lot of things changed while building the thing, so beware. Because I didn&amp;#8217;t cap the ends of the central section, it&amp;#8217;s not rigid, so I put in cable cross-stays on the back to make it stable (it&amp;#8217;s still fairly wobbly &amp;#8212; no fasteners!). I took out a chunk of the top part of the legs, to create the three-layered system&amp;#160;above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7967635154/&#34; title=&#34;Desk Plans by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8459/7967635154_fe58df544b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;386&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Desk Plans&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7967636932/&#34; title=&#34;Desk Plans by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8456/7967636932_38b9b6bc21.jpg&#34; width=&#34;386&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Desk Plans&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The stains are shellac. I love that stuff.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the 4 &amp;times; 8 birch-veneer plywood board, specc&amp;#8217;d out to be cut. I had the guys at Home Depot do all of the big cuts &amp;#8212; which they did, albeit, messily. I did the rest with a cheap-o (cordless!) circular&amp;#160;saw. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/samjacoby/7967639124/&#34; title=&#34;Desk Plans by s_jacoby, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8438/7967639124_ae914087d6.jpg&#34; width=&#34;394&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Desk Plans&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the tricky part, the detail of the leg-surface connection. The basic angle I calculated was 68.2&amp;deg;, which worked out reasonable well. If it&amp;#8217;s too shallow, your legs could bow&amp;#8212;too steep, and well, you&amp;#8217;ve just made a more-or-less regular desk. Oh, and I beveled the bottom of each leg so that it stands flat&amp;#8212;but that you&amp;#8217;d do&amp;#160;automatically. &lt;/p&gt; 
        </content>
    </entry>
        </feed>